<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The cheating solliciter cheated being a true and perfect relation of the life and death of Richard Farr : with an exact character of his wench, Mrs. Eleanor Chadwick : both executed at Tyburn, the 12th of April last past.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1665</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 107 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 30 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A32779</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing C3766</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R35567</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">15367230</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 15367230</idno>
            <idno type="VID">103523</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A32779)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 103523)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1148:2)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The cheating solliciter cheated being a true and perfect relation of the life and death of Richard Farr : with an exact character of his wench, Mrs. Eleanor Chadwick : both executed at Tyburn, the 12th of April last past.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>58 p., [1] leaf of plates : ill.  </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for T.J.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1665.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imperfect: cropped and tightly bound, with print show-through and loss of print.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Farr, Richard, d. 1665?</term>
               <term>Chadwick, Eleanor, d. 1665?</term>
               <term>Swindlers and swindling --  England.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>Leah Yurasek</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>Leah Yurasek</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="frontispiece">
            <pb facs="tcp:103523:1"/>
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <sp>
                     <p>'Tis Felony.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <p>Thou are mine.</p>
                  </sp>
                  <sp>
                     <p>'Tis but a Cheat.</p>
                  </sp>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:103523:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>THE Cheating Solliciter CHEATED: BEING A True and Perfect <hi>Relation</hi> of the <hi>LIFE</hi> and <hi>DEATH</hi> OF RICHARD FARR. <hi>WITH</hi> An Exact Character of his Wench, Mrs. <hi>ELEANOR CHADWICK.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Both Executed at <hi>Tyburn,</hi> the 12th. of <hi>April,</hi> laſt paſt.</p>
            <q>
               <l>— <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>t rem faciam rem,</l>
               <l>Si poſſim recte, ſi non quocunque modo rem.</l>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>T J</hi> 1665</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:103523:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:103523:2"/>
            <head>THE <hi>LIFE</hi> and <hi>DEATH</hi> OF Richard Farr.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">S</seg>Ince Example hath ſo great an influence upon the Lives and Actions of Men, as that we find they are more wrought upon thereby, than by the grave and ſober Counſells, Inſtructions, and Precepts, even of the moſt Wiſe and Learned. And ſeeing that preceding Generations, have been careful to Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>municate to their Poſterity, an Account of the Lives, not only of the Good and Vertuous, and of ſuch as have done great and eminent things for their Country; but alſo of the moſt Flagitious and Criminal: As by the ſmooth and beau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiful Draughts of the One, to allure to the love and practi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ce of Vertue: ſo by the ugly, dreadful and frightly Aſpects of the Other, to deterr from the commitment, of Vice. I cannot but think, that I ſhall perform, both an accepta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, and ſerviceable Work to my Country, in expoſing this ſubtil Gameſter, and tracing him through all the Maen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, Intrigues and Mazes of his Life, to the ſhameful and deſerved Period thereof at <hi>Tyburn.</hi> And by his Example, convince the ſecure and preſuming Offender, that wick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Actions, though of never ſo fine and curious ſpinning,
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:103523:3"/>though contrived and executed with the greateſt privacy, cunning and diſguiſe imaginable, ſhall yet certainly have their proper and natural Effect, and ſad Cataſtrophe: And that wronging the Innocent by Tricks ahd Cheats; and ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king from them what they have by Power and Violence, are but <hi>Two Wayes, that lead to the ſame Wood.</hi> Not is it the leaſt Benefit, that I conceive a Publication of this nature may do to the Publick, by informing the weak and ſimple of the Abuſes and Cheats put upon others, and thereby (as it were) fore-arming them, to preſerve them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves from the like. But to my Work.</p>
            <p>RICHARD FARR was born in <hi>Warwickſhire,</hi> near <hi>Killingworth;</hi> his Father a Tanner, of honeſt fame and reputation: his Mother ſuſpected, and ſomewhat tal'kd of in her Youth; but too too viſibly a Partaker with her Son, now in her Age. Her Husband and ſhe parting upon Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>content (whereof ſhe is conceived to have given the Cauſe) ſhe came up to <hi>London,</hi> bringing with her this her Son <hi>Richard,</hi> then a Boy, of about Nine or Ten Years of Age: Where they lived together (moſt about <hi>Covent-Garden</hi>) in mean Condition; ſhe, in the nature of a Chair-woman, working for her Living: and her Son plying up and down Streets, as a Link-Boy, toward his; and going to and fro on Errands for People, to whoſe Houſes his Mother did re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſort. This looſe and unfixed kind of Life, muſt needs have begotten in him an ill habit of Mind; which being impro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved by the ſtrength of his natural Parts, a ſharp Wit, a quick Apprehenſion, and a ſolid and deep Judgement; but a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove all, a moſt tenacious Memory (whereby whatſoever he either read, or heard diſcourſed in Company, he made his own) did exactly ſquare and fit him for the carrying on
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:103523:3"/>of his miſchievous Contrivances, with ſuch continued impunity. Nor was he a little beholding to his manner of Speech (whether natural, or deſigned and artificial, I can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not affirm) which being ſlow and drawling, but ſmotth and oylie, did give him a more eaſie admittance into the acquaintance and familiarity of thoſe he had Deſign upon: And it hath been obſerved, by Perſons that have had much Converſe and Controverſie with him, that he had ſo full and compleat a Command over his Paſſions, as that nothing could provoke him in Company to Anger, or move him from his cloſe and reſerved Guard: Yet was he of a moſt implacable and revengeful Spirit (for he hath ſometimes attempted a private Stabb, where he could not otherwiſe obtain his will) And 'tis notorious, by too many ſurviving Inſtances, in and about the City, that whoſoever was ſo hardy, as (in proſecution of his own, or his Friends right) to enter Conteſt with him, he ſeldom left him, till either quite ruin'd, or ſo weakned, as that he had better have ſate down contented with his firſt Loſs. Nay 'twill appear, by many Particulars in this Relation, that where he could come to place his Engines, ſo as to have full hold, he would do his work at firſt ſo thorough<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, as to leave them in an abſolute incapacity of helping themſelves, or hurting him. And indeed it will ſeem no wonder, if to the conſideration of his natural Parts, and what he muſt needs have acquired in ſo many years pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctice (wherein he ran through all the Courts and Priſons about <hi>London</hi>) we ſhall add thoſe petty advantages of a Conſcience that boggled at nothing, and Inſtruments that would both do and ſwear whatſoever he would have them.</p>
            <p>By this imployment in errands &amp; other petty buſineſſes
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:103523:4"/>for Gentlemen, having gotten good cloaths on his back, and a little money in his pocket; he next gets him a wife, <hi>Elizabeth Forreſt</hi> a Tailors daughter in <hi>Charles</hi> ſtreet, ſometime ſervant to Mis Stanier, on whom he plaid this laſt notorious prank, for which he was hang'd.</p>
            <p>His wife being a plain woman (not ſquared for his in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended deſignes) he ſoon grew weary of her. Left her. She for her livelihood turnned Landreſſe to Gentlemen, and among the reſt to Mr. Skipwith; by which when Farr perceived ſhe had gotten a little money, he would then live with her again, and by what ſhe had ſcraped toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, and ſome further aſſiſtance of her Maſters, he took a little ſhop ('twas indeed a cellar) in Harts ſtreet, where he ſold chandlary ware and band ſtrings, and made periwigs for Gentlemen, and here he committed his firſt fact that was taken notice off and by it ſtockt himſelf to a capacity of doing many more.</p>
            <p>One <hi>Sarah</hi> that uſed to go up and down to ſell or diſpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſe of Rings, Iewells and the like, came (as ſhe uſed to do) to <hi>Farrs</hi> houſe with her Basket, (which ſhe commonly carried a bout wich her) and in it a box of Rings belon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging to one Mis Baker of about forty or fifty pound value. <hi>Farr</hi> made a ſhiſt to nimme away the box and Rings. She miſt them not till ſhe came where ſhe intended to diſpoſe of them, then ſhe went back, taxed <hi>Farr;</hi> he denied and forſwore them. But at length it was diſcovered by one of the rings that was found at a Goldſmiths, who confeſſed that he bought it of <hi>Farr;</hi> who was thereupon apprehend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded, and committed to the <hi>Gatehouſe,</hi> where he lay about 6 weeks (a very good ſchool for ſo apt a ſchollar.) from thence he was removed to <hi>Newgate</hi> in Order to his tryall;
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:103523:4"/>the Goldſmith was ready to have ſworn againſt him, but <hi>Sarah,</hi> who ſhould have proſecuted him had a freak came into her head, ran out of the Court, ſaying ſhe would not be guilty of taking away any mans life. So he was acquit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted; of which he made ſo good uſe, by his fair tongue, that many beleived him innocent. And Mr. <hi>Skipwith</hi> ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving at <hi>Farrs</hi> motion bought of one <hi>Halfepenny</hi> 2 or 3 Tenements in <hi>Phenix Alley</hi> by <hi>Long Acre,</hi> put him in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to poſſeſſion, and ſealed him a leaſe of them (the credit of which he ſo exceedingly improv'd to his further Rogue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries) and took lodgings with him, and removed his goods thither, ſome looſe, moſt in trunks. Mr. Skipwith being diverted by buſines, and often (being for aweek or fort<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>night together) at his brothers in <hi>Hartfordſhire, Farr</hi> had his opportunity to do as he pleaſed; he took away out of his chamber firſt ſuch things as were looſe which Mr. Skipwith took little notice, as thinking they were layd ſomewhere elſe. Afterwards he got a falſe key to his desk, where all the keyes of his trunks were, which he ranſakt of the beſt and choiceſt goods. And when Mr. <hi>Skipwith</hi> miſt them and askt <hi>Farr</hi> about them, He told him, that Mr. <hi>Stanton</hi> the upholſter had (amongſt the things that he layd claim to as Mis. <hi>Rayes</hi>) taken away out of his trunks, wherein were the things he miſt, &amp; adviſed him to ſue him, offering himſelf a witnes both to the fact, and alſo to the value of the trunk. Mr. <hi>Skipwith</hi> hereupon went to the Upholſter, demanded his trunk, and had it ſent home. When he opened it: Farr (having called ſome neighbours for witneſſes) was preſent; The trunk was empty, exce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pting ſome few things of no value. <hi>Farr</hi> thereupon prayed them to take notice that the Lock of the trunk had been taken of, for the nayles were not clincht, on the inſide &amp;
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:103523:5"/>indeed himſelf at the robbing of the tru<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>k had ſo drawn off the lock, and when the upholſter came to ſeize Mis. <hi>Rayes</hi> goods, purpoſely clapt it in amongſt them for adiſguiſe &amp; cloak of what he had done; preſt M. <hi>Skipwith</hi> again to ſue him. But he began now more to ſuſpect <hi>Farr</hi> then the upholſter, which <hi>Farr</hi> perceiving, and knowing that the conſequence of it muſt be the diſcovery of him, he cryed whore firſt, and by way of prevention clapt an Action of 120 pound debt upon him, and while he was in the cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtody of the Baylies removed all his other goods. Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon Mr. <hi>Skipwith</hi> took out a warrant againſt him, took alſo with him two Conſtables and two Beadles to exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute it. They found moſt of the goods in rhe houſe; a watch, a ſilver bottle, a pair of ſilkſtockings, and ſome jewells about him. They had him before Iuſtice Peaps, who committed him to Newgate. The firſt ſeſſions he got his tryall put off; but was to remaine in priſon without bayle; yet within tendayes he prevailed with his keeper to go out with him: he ſerved a warrant upon Mr. Skipwith, and ſwore felony againſt him before the ſaid Iuſtice: The next ſeſſions <hi>Farr</hi> came to tryall: Mr. Skipwith, the two Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtables &amp; two Beadles ſwore the goods were found about him: But he ſo ordered his buſines by croſſe oaths that he was acquitted; having his liberty he continually vexed him with freſh ſuits and informations for the ſpace of 3 or 4 years, inſomuch that the Gentleman to be rid of ſuch a raſcall betook himſelf for ſome time to travell.</p>
            <p>I made mention a little before of Mis. <hi>Ray</hi> a midwife; I ſhall now give a Relation of that affaire. Mis. <hi>Ray</hi> by will made Mr. <hi>Stanton</hi> her Executor and <hi>Farr</hi> overſeer of her will. The Executor finding <hi>Farr</hi> to be knowing and
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:103523:5"/>thinking him to be honeſt, intruſted him to manage the whole buſines.</p>
            <p>He ſeizd upon all the goods and remov'd them to his own houſe, and intentionally wholly to his own uſe; And Mr. Stanton the Eexecutor was forced to get them from him by <hi>Replevy,</hi> and in removing of them <hi>Farr</hi> deſignedly clapt Mr. Skiwiths trunk, which he had robd, amongſt them, and ſome few things of his own. Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon to ground his vexatious Actions at law, and not prevailing with Mr. Skipwith to meddle, he went, &amp; in his name laid claim to ſeverall goods as his, which did indeed belong to Mis. <hi>Ray,</hi> and had them delivered unto him, and did from himſelf and otheers create ſo much trouble to the Gentleman, that he had better to have given 200 pound then have been made Executor.</p>
            <p>Now being weary of his wife and able to live without her, and having found out one (Mis. Chadwick) fitter for his purpoſe and of a more ſuitable temper, found out this way to be rid of her. He prevailed with her (part<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly by Threatnings &amp; partly by ſuggeſtion of great be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefit to themſelvs by it) to ſwear her ſelf with child by a Gentleman he had ſome controverſy with; ſhe went with him to a Iuſtice to ſwear it, but when the Iuſtice under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtood what it was ſhe was about to ſwear, he told her of the Danger ſhe brought her ſelf into; (for it was when <hi>Olivers</hi> Act againſt adultery was in force) where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon ſhe recoyled and would not do it: But her huſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band took advantage of what ſhe had confeſſed, though tis thought ſhe was no way guilty, and turnd her out of Doores to ſhift for her ſelf: refuſing alſo to keep the Childe.</p>
            <p>Mr SK. Sold his Houſes to the Mr of the <hi>Goat-Tavern</hi> in
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:103523:6"/>
               <hi>Smithfield;</hi> whom <hi>Farr</hi> foon finding to be a Perſon, ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>what better able to deal with him, faceth about, and pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceth his Artillery againſt a more eaſie Fort; one Mr. <hi>Dur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>win,</hi> a Glazier, in the <hi>Cole-Yard,</hi> near <hi>Drury-Lane,</hi> his an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tient and real Friend, and good Benefactor. He forgeth a Leaſe to himſelf, from Mr. <hi>Skip.</hi> at an eaſie Rent; offers and ſells this Leaſe to his ſaid Friend <hi>Durwin;</hi> a good pen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nyworth (if he could have made his bargain good) de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>livereth Poſſeſſion, and Mr. <hi>Durwin</hi> cometh, and liveth in it. Not long after, the head-Landlord comes to demand the Rent of the Tenant in Poſſeſſion, together with all the Arrears due from <hi>Farr;</hi> he telleth <hi>Farr</hi> of it, but nothing o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> redreſs from him. The Tenant not paying it, his Goods were ſeized on by the Landlord, his Fine paid to <hi>Farr</hi> utter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly loſt, and himſelf ejected the Houſe. Upon this hard meaſure, he ſues <hi>Farr</hi> upon the Covenants of his Leaſe; but <hi>(Impar Congreſſus) Farr</hi> was too hard for him; and being provoked, turn'd upon him, and never left, till (after his Eſtate was almoſt conſumed in Law) he got him a Priſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner into <hi>Newgate,</hi> where for grief he dyed.</p>
            <p>Nor was he much kinder to his Relations after hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> death; for he endeavoured, by a forg'd Deed, to have Cheated the Widow of ſome Tenements, in the ſaid <hi>Cole-Yard;</hi> and did really Cheat his Daughter (by a Trick) of 1<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Pound, in ready Money, beſides houſhold Goods, and wearing Apparel.</p>
            <p>And it is worth the remembring, the whilſt M<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Durwin</hi> lived in the Houſe, <hi>Farr</hi> forged a Deed of Sal<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> to himſelf, of the Fee ſimple, from Mr. <hi>Skip.</hi> and brought a Gentleman, a Draper in <hi>Fleet-Street,</hi> to ſee it, with intent of buying it (and no doubt but <hi>Farr</hi> would have ſold him a Pennyworth, rather than no<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:103523:6"/>taken his Money) But the Gentleman enquiring of Mrs. <hi>Durwin,</hi> what Rent ſhe paid, and many other Particulars, raiſed in her a jealouſie of <hi>Farr</hi>'s intentions, ſo that ſhe ask'd the Gentleman, if it were ſo; who ſaying <hi>Yes,</hi> the Woman preſently cryed out, <hi>O Lord! Sir, the Houſe is none of his,</hi> &amp;c. Whereby ſhe diſap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed <hi>Farr</hi> of his Project: And this was it, that did principally provoke him, to deal ſo miſchievouſly with her Husband, her ſelf, and Daughter.</p>
            <p>Theſe late Troubles of his, as they did really add to his Experience; and his ſucceſs in them (faming him to be <hi>A Cunning Fellow in the Law</hi>) much further him in the Employment, which he afterwards took up, and practiſed, to the ruine of ſo many Families, I mean that of a Solliciter: So did the great expenſiveneſs of them, bring him to a low ebb in his Pocket, whereby he was forced to content himſelf, for the preſent, with an Employment of a lower Orb. For now did he enter himſelf a Souldier in <hi>Barkſtead</hi>'s Regiment; though at the ſame time (as Captain) he commanded a Company of Privateers (<hi>Anglice</hi> Night-Thieves) having made a Convenience, to goe in and out of his own Houſe, at any time, without either noiſe or notice: And he was the only Man, that diſpoſed of what was gotten, either by ſale or pawn, for which he had brokeage, and the lickings of his fingers to boot; and this trade of recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving and diſpoſing ſtollen Goods, 'tis thought he uſed to his laſt. He alſo ſold Bottle-Ale, and if he lik'd his Chapman, would help him to a Cure for his Concupi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcence; and by theſe means, and freedom from Law-Suits, he got Money into his Pocket, and put himſelf into an handſome Garb. And now if any Wrangling,
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:103523:7"/>Controverſie, Law-Suit, or Buſineſs of Difficulty, aroſe among the Neighbourhood, who but Mr. <hi>Farr</hi> for a Solliciter? If (as the livelyhood of that end of the Town depends much upon Lodgings) any Perſon, having taken a large Houſe, wanted Hangings, and other Furniture, who but Mr. <hi>Farr</hi> for a Broker? If a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny wanted a ſumm of Money, upon good ſecurity, who but Mr. <hi>Farr</hi> for a Procurer? Now did he appear in his Pluſh-Coat, and ſometimes with his Pantaloons and Muff: Now had he his variety of Shapes and Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parel, ſutable to the Deſignes he intended: Now did his Friends (and Strangers, that knew him not) Court; and his Enemies, that knew him, ſtand in awe, and fear him.</p>
            <p>And if it be true (which is, by the frequent Obſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation of many, grown into a Proverbial Maxim) <hi>That there is no Man, but hath in his Life-time, ſome</hi> (at leaſt one) <hi>Opportunity to promote himſelf:</hi> So this certainly was that very point of time, wherein this Perſon might have laid the Foundation to himſelf, of a better Life, and more happy Death. But he had ſo much of the Fate of a Knave upon him, that he knew not how to be honeſt, though never ſo much to his own advantage; ſo that in the whole courſe of his Employment, he ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver was intruſted by any, whom he did not Cheat; never came to the acquaintance of a plain, and honeſt-meaning man, whom he did not circumvent; never had an Adverſary, whom he would not venture Soul and Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy to deſtroy; nor a Friend, whom he would not for Money ſell and betray, as will clearly appear by the following Liſt.</p>
            <pb n="11" facs="tcp:103523:7"/>
            <p>
               <hi>Farr</hi>'s Wife having been Servant to Madam <hi>Staneir,</hi> as is before ſaid, <hi>Farr</hi> thereby became acquainted with her, was welcome to her Houſe and Table, did buſineſs for her; in which time ſhe loſt many things, which ſhe either did not preſently miſs, or little ſuſpected <hi>Farr</hi> to have been the Thief: Till at length, he ſtole from her a little Bitch, that ſhe brought with her out of <hi>France,</hi> (for which ſhe had a great love and fancy) and would not reſtore her; whereat the Gentlewoman was very angry, fore-warned him her Houſe, and called in the Money ſhe had lent him: He, in requital, forged Bills of her hand, for Money due to him; arreſted her no leſs than four ſeveral times, by Bill of <hi>Mid.</hi> in one day; and not ſatisfied with this, indited her for her Life, for Words ſpoken againſt the then Powers; but ſhe was ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quitted.</p>
            <p>One Mrs. <hi>Andrewes,</hi> who lived then in St. <hi>Martins-Lane,</hi> having ſpoken to him, to help her to 100 Pound, he promiſed to do it, but would not except any leſs Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>curity, than a Judgement of all ſhe had; which ſhe yielded to: He brought with him a Warrant of Attor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, and two of his Complices to witneſs it, and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vailed with her to ſeal it; telling her, That he would goe with her preſently to the Gentleman, that would pay the Money: He carried her to a Houſe, where he had deſigned before, that the Gentleman ſhould not be within; ſo they parted, and appointed to goe again next day: But <hi>Farr</hi> came to her no more, till he came with an Execution, and ſeized all ſhe had, to her utter ruine.</p>
            <p>The like he did by one Mrs. <hi>Manly,</hi> to whom having promiſed the loan of 50 Pound (upon the ſame ſecurity
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:103523:8"/>that he had from Mrs. <hi>Andrewes</hi>) he came to her, and told her, That his Money did not come in as he expect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed; but, that he might not diſappiont her, he had there a Leaſe of a Houſe, which coſt him, and was worth 300 Pound, upon which ſhe might eaſily borrow 50 Pound (but engaged her not to mortgage it for more) The poor Gentlewoman, little ſuſpecting him (living then in ſuch a Garb, and making ſuch a buſtle in the World) upon receipt of his Leaſe, ſealed his Warrant for Judgement: But when the went to bor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row the 50 Pound, and enquiry was thereupon made into the Leaſe, ſhe found the Houſe as he ſaid, and the Leaſe to be real, but the Houſe taken at the higheſt rack Rent, and ſo the Leaſe not worth a farthing: She there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon upon went to ſeek out <hi>Farr,</hi> who would not be ſpoken with, till he came, and took away all in Execution, which broke the poor Womans heart.</p>
            <p>In the ſame nature did he ſerve the Lady <hi>Anderſon,</hi> and Dr. <hi>Charlton</hi>'s Lady, when her Husband, in the late Troubles, was beyond Sea; and many others; which having effected by the ſame means, and in the ſame manner, I ſhall forbear the Particulars, leſt it ſhould ſeem repetition; and, for variety ſake, give you one of his Tricks, ſomewhat more Comical.</p>
            <p>Wanting a ſumm of Money, he ſet his Wits to work, and fram'd his Plot thus: He habits himſelf like a Country Grazier, comes into a great Inn in <hi>Smithfield,</hi> asks for the Maſter of it, and calls for a Flaggon of Beer, to drink with him. When the Inn-keeper came, he ask'd him, Whether ſuch a Man (naming a great <hi>Lincoln-ſhire</hi> Grazier, that uſed to Inn there) were yet come to Town: The Man replyed, <hi>No:</hi> At which <hi>Farr</hi>
               <pb n="13" facs="tcp:103523:8"/>ſeemed to wonder; for he ſaid, he parted with him up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the Road, but two Nights before; and that both their Cattel were coming up together; and that he came before, only becauſe he was to have a great Tryal, as on the Morrow. By and by in comes <hi>Chad.</hi> (<hi>Farr</hi>'s Friend, and one of his Swearers, till convicted for Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jury) habited like a Drover. Quoth <hi>Farr, How now</hi> Dick? <hi>What's the beſt Newes? Are my Cattel come?</hi> He, bare-header, and with a long ſcrape, anſwered, <hi>No Sir; The great py'd Oxe is fallen lame, ſo that we were forc'd to ſtay at ſuch a Place</hi> (naming a Town on the Road) <hi>Why then</hi> (ſayes <hi>Farr</hi>) <hi>my Cattel will not be here to Night: No,</hi> ſaith <hi>Chad. 'Tis well if they get them here ſoon enough for to Morrow Market:</hi> At that <hi>Farr</hi> ſtamp'd, and ſwore he knew not what he ſhould do, for he wanted Money to prepare for his Morrows Tryal (which he pretended to be of great Conſequence, and that therefore he muſt retain the greateſt Council he could get) <hi>Farr</hi> then ask<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, Whether his Friend (naming the Graſier) was come: <hi>Chad.</hi> replyed, <hi>No; He ſtayes to come along with the Cattel, for he hath ſome of his fallen lame too:</hi> At which <hi>Farr</hi> ſeemed exceedingly diſcontented, as not knowing what to do. Whereupon the Inn-keeper believing, from their diſcourſe, and the behaviour of <hi>Chad.</hi> to his ſuppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed Maſter, that he was really a great Grazier, and could not have leſs than 5 or 600 Pounds worth of Cattel coming up; asked him, What Money would ſerve his turn: He ſaid, 20 Pound: The Inn-keeper prayed him not to trouble himſelf then, for he would ſupply him ſo farr as 20 or 30 Pound went: Which <hi>Farr,</hi> with great acknowledgement of the Civility, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cepted; and promiſed to repay it on the Morrow: The
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:103523:9"/>Inn-keeper fetch'd him 20 Pound, and <hi>Farr</hi> received it, and went away, as being in haft upon his buſineſs; ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to <hi>Chad. Come</hi> Dick, <hi>goe you along with me, for I ſhall have occaſion to ſend you on an Errand or two:</hi> So away they went; but the Inn-keeper heard no more of his Grazier.</p>
            <p>Being at Mr. <hi>Durwins</hi> (formerly mentioned) in <hi>Ploenix-Alley,</hi> there came in one Mr. <hi>Hollinsby,</hi> a <hi>Blackwel-Hall</hi> Factor; who, in diſcourſe, was telling him, That a Cuſtomer of his, a Weſt-Country Wea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver, had a Parcel of Sayes to ſell, and that he would ſell them a Pennyworth, and would take half his Money down, and half at ſix Months end. <hi>Farr</hi> told him, He would help him to a Cuſtomer, and deſired, they might be ſent into his Houſe, and laid in the Belcony Room, one pair of Stairs, and he did not queſtion, to give an account of them, by next Morning. The Goods were accordingly ſent in, and laid where he order'd, himſelf being then not at home. <hi>Farr</hi> conveys away the Goods, into a Vault, or Common-Shore, that he could goe into, out of his Cellar; breaks a Pane of Glaſs out of the Belcony Door, and ſets the Door open (as if ſome Thief had, by breaking the Glaſs, put in his hand, and opened the Door, and ſtole the Sayes away) When Mr. <hi>Hollinsby,</hi> and his Country Chapman, came next Morning, <hi>Farr</hi> pretended himſelf Robb'd, and ſo Cheated the poor Man of his Goods, nor could he ever get a farthing ſatisfaction.</p>
            <p>About this time alſo, a young Gentlewoman, upon ſome diſcontent and difference, by his advice, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drew her ſelf (with what of her moſt rich Goods ſhe could take with her) from her Friends, to Lodgings,
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:103523:9"/>which he provided for her, in <hi>Blackmores-Alley;</hi> where, when ſhe had continued for ſometime, he perſwaded her to remove to other Lodgings, which he had taken for her, more private and convenient, whereunto ſhe conſented; and he, under colour of removing her Goods to the ſaid new Lodgings, conveyed them all a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way, leaving her nothing but her Smock, and an under-Petticoat, and never came near her afterwards.</p>
            <p>He coming in the Garb of a Gentleman, to Mr. <hi>New<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man,</hi> a great Builder in <hi>Lincolns-Inn-Fields,</hi> took of him one of his Houſes there, and lived in it paying him the firſt Quarters Rent punctually, but afterwards would not pay any: When he was run three Quarters behind, his Landlord thought it time to look after him; and having heard ſomething of his former manners, did not care how ſoon he was rid of ſuch a Tenant; he therefore ſues him for his Arrears of Rent, and alſo ſeals a Leaſe of Ejectment againſt him. but <hi>Farr</hi> alters the Month of Mr. <hi>Newman</hi>'s Acquittance, which he gave him for his firſt Quarters Rent; and at the Tryal, had his Witneſſes to ſwear, the alteration of the word, by Mr. <hi>Newman</hi> himſelf, when the Money was paid; and ſo Mr. <hi>Newman</hi> loſt his three Quarters Rent, his Charges, and was overthrown in his Ejectment, as having ſued before his time. <hi>Farr,</hi> knowing there was no ſtaying in the Houſe for him, takes away the Lead out of the Belcony, and the Leaden Pipes, and ſells them; finds a Tenant, of whom he takes a Fine, and lets it at a ſmall Rent, and ſo leaves him in the Houſe, to loſe his Fine, and anſwer for the waſte he himſelf had done.</p>
            <pb n="16" facs="tcp:103523:10"/>
            <p>He, with one of his Complices, coming into a Coffee-houſe, ſate down at a Table, where was other Company; <hi>Farr</hi> drew out his Watch, pretending to ſee what a Clock it was: A Gentleman ſitting by, ask<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed him, What it was a Clock; he thereupon gave him his Watch to look: When he had ſeen, <hi>Farr</hi>'s Friend took the Watch from him, as if he alſo would ſee, what time of the Day it was, and with it went away: <hi>Farr</hi> taking no notice thereof; and the Gentleman que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtioning nothing, for that he preſum'd him to be <hi>Farr</hi>'s Friend and Acquaintance (as indeed he was) The Man being gone, <hi>Farr</hi> ask'd the Gentleman for his Watch: He replyed, That his Friend had it: <hi>Farr</hi> ſaid, He was no Friend of his, nor did he know him; and told him, He muſt look for his Watch from him; took witneſs of the By-ſtanders, That he had delivered the Watch into his hands; ſued him for the Watch, and recovered the value of it: And this very Watch, was afterwards found at a Place, Pawn'd by <hi>Farr</hi> him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf.</p>
            <p>A Woman living near St. <hi>Giles</hi>'s Church in <hi>Holborn,</hi> was, by a forg'd Deed of his, ejected her Houſe, and her Goods ſeiz'd on, whereupon the poor Woman hanged her ſelf.</p>
            <p>He having had ſome dealing with one Mr. <hi>Taylor,</hi> and received ſome Money for him, and paid it again, by his Order; deſired then to have a general Releaſe from him, which the Man was willing to do: But <hi>Farr,</hi> inſtead of a Releaſe, preſented him with a Warrant of Attorney, for a Judgement for 40 Pound; which the unwary Man ſate his hand to, and a while after was taken in Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, and forced to pay the Money.</p>
            <pb n="17" facs="tcp:103523:10"/>
            <p>He played his Pranks very ſeverely upon one Mr. <hi>Alexander,</hi> then the King's Shooemaker; with whom he having ſome ſmall Concern, went and made Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaint to the <hi>Green-Cloath,</hi> and deſired liberty to ſue him: He had granted him an Order to ſummon in Mr. <hi>Alexander,</hi> which he never did; but he, and <hi>Chad.</hi> whom he brought with him, making Oath, that he had ſummons, and that he did contemptuouſly diſobey the ſame, he had liberty granted him, to ſue him; which he did; and, by the help of good Witneſſes, who ſwore treble the Debt, had Judgement; which Mr. <hi>Alexander</hi> ſatisfied, but neglected to ſee Satisfa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction acknowledged upon Record: So that <hi>Farr,</hi> ſome time after, ſerv'd the Execution upon his Goods, when he was out of Town, and his Wife was forc'd to pay it a ſecond time. He ſerv'd it alſo a third time on his Perſon; but he then choſe rather to goe to the <hi>Gate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>houſe,</hi> than pay the Money into hands, whence there was no hope of Redemption; and there continued a Priſoner till Term, and then was diſcharged: But <hi>Farr</hi> durſt not appear for his Ears.</p>
            <p>A Friend of <hi>Farr</hi>'s, being ſued by one Mr. <hi>John Wot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton,</hi> a Country Man, upon a Bond of 100 Pound, em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed <hi>Farr</hi> as a Solliciter. When <hi>Farr</hi> heard, that Mr. <hi>Wotton</hi> was come to Town, in order to his Tryal; he, and his truſty Friend <hi>Chad.</hi> went to him, to his Inn, pretending to make an end of the Buſineſs, but intending only to have a certain knowledge of his Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon; and when the Buſineſs came to Tryal, <hi>Farr</hi> and <hi>Chad.</hi> ſwore the Bond ſatisfied; and ſo Mr. <hi>Wotton</hi> loſt both his Money, and his Charges.</p>
            <pb n="18" facs="tcp:103523:11"/>
            <p>Another Roguery he acted (beyond humanity) a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt one Mr. <hi>Green,</hi> an antient Man, living in <hi>Covent-Garden,</hi> and a ſingle Man, and well to paſs: For when he was juſt upon the point of Dying, and not ſenſible, <hi>Farr</hi> came with an Execution (which all men believe to be forg'd) and took away all his Goods, but the very Bed he lay upon; and for this was never ſo much as queſtion'd.</p>
            <p>One Project he made a very frequent and beneficial uſe of, which was this: When any Man, whom he knew, dyed in ſuch a Condition, as that the Widow, Heir at Law, would not adminiſter or meddle, but leave what there was, to be divided amongſt the Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors; he would be ſure, by a forg'd Bond, to make himſelf a Principal Creditor; and as ſuch, take out Letters of Adminiſtration, and get into his hands what he could, and never part with a farthing to any of the other Creditors.</p>
            <p>And another way he had, of ſomewhat a more ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruſe and myſterious reach, <hi>viz.</hi> He would combine with a poor Fellow to be Arreſted, for ſome ſmall in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>conſiderable matter; and upon pretence of not being a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to get Bayl, turn himſelf over to <hi>Ludgate;</hi> where, upon pitty to the Condition of the Man, and the ſmall<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of that againſt him, they would take any ſlender Security, for his true Impriſonment, and let him goe abroad: Then would <hi>Farr,</hi> having a Bond of the Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon for that purpoſe, enter privately an Action againſt the Priſoner, to a conſiderable value; and then the Priſoner would run away, and his Security not be found; and ſo <hi>Farr</hi> would bring his Action againſt the Keeper, and his Swearers to atteſt the Bond, and recover the Money.</p>
            <pb n="19" facs="tcp:103523:11"/>
            <p>There is one Mrs. <hi>Lewis,</hi> now a Priſoner to <hi>Ludgate,</hi> a ſad Inſtance of his miſchievous malice: For having pawned to her divers Goods, to the value of 15 Pound, he afterwards cauſed one of his Agents, to bring an Action of <hi>Trover</hi> againſt her, for the ſaid Goods, as his, and ſo fetch'd them out of her hands; for which ſhe be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginning to vex him by a Sute, he forged a Bond, of a conſiderable ſumm, and arreſted her; never leaving, till he brought her to the Place and Condition wherein ſhe now is.</p>
            <p>The like Cheat (and Revenge after it) did he put upon one Mr. <hi>P.</hi> a Goldſmith, with whom he did often deal (as Broker) both for buying and ſelling. Paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing by his Shop, he obſerved a rich Locket of Dia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monds, of good value: He told Mrs. <hi>P.</hi> who for the moſt part kept the Shop, and was then in it, That he knew a Lady would buy the Locket, and at a Price had it delivered to him, to ſhew the Lady: He got it pattern'd exactly, by a Locket of Briſtol Stones; and took his opportunity to come, when only the Appren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice, a young Lad, was there, and delivered it to him, in preſence of a Gentleman, whom he brought with him, to witneſs it, bidding him to carry it in to his Miſtreſs; who receiving it, took not ſo much no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice of it at firſt, as to perceive the Cheat, but ſoon after did; but to little purpoſe, for <hi>Farr</hi> was gone: And being afterwards taxed, he denied the thing ſtoutly; So the Goldſmith ſued him, but to no effect; for obſerve what a Freak <hi>Farr</hi> finds out, to ſuperſede him in his Proſecution.</p>
            <p>Mr. <hi>P.</hi> one of the King's Trumpeters, having loſt his Trumpet, which he much valued for its goodneſs,
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:103523:12"/>ſpent much money and time in looking after it, but could not retrive it. <hi>Farr</hi> hearing of it, repairs to him, and told him, He knew where his Trumpet had been: The Gentleman glad thereof, went preſently with him: He directed him to this Mr. <hi>P.</hi> his Houſe, where he made demand of his Trumpet: The Goldſmith denied his having any ſuch thing: Whereupon the Trumpeter went to the Place, where he had left <hi>Farr,</hi> and his Friend, expecting the iſſue; and told <hi>Farr,</hi> what the Goldſmith ſaid: <hi>Farr</hi> anſwered, That he ſaw it in his hands at ſuch a time, and ſo did that his Friend; and that, if he would have the Goldſmith, by a War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant, before a Juſtice, they would both ſwear it; and they were as good as their words. The Goldſmith, fearing the dangerous Conſequence (not only to his Eſtate, but his Life alſo) of having to do with ſuch Swearers; gave the Gentleman Satisfaction for his Trumpet, and let fall his Sure againſt <hi>Farr</hi> for his Locket.</p>
            <p>He alſo put the Change upon a Jewellers Apprentice (his Friend) in <hi>Crutched-Fryers;</hi> taking away a very large Diamond, and leaving a Briſtol Stone in the room of it.</p>
            <p>When he was a Priſoner in the <hi>Kings-Bench</hi> in <hi>Southwark,</hi> he obſerved a pretty Garden-houſe to ſtand empty; he thought it pitty it ſhould want a Tenant, and reſolved on this Plot: He went to the Landlord, in a very gentile Garb; and told him, He had taken much notice of ſuch a Houſe, and had a great mind to build himſelf one exactly after that pattern; and deſired, That he might have the liberty, to bring a Carpenter, go take a juſt meaſure of the ſcantling. The Gentleman
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:103523:12"/>could not deny ſo ſmall a Civility; but told him, that he ſhould do it when he pleaſed. He thereupon went to a Carpenter, and told him; That he was about to buy a Houſe hard by; deſiring him, to goe along with him, and give him his eſtimate of it. The Carpenter went readily with him; they call upon the Landlord, and ſo goe to the Houſe together. The Carpenter took an exact account of the Butts and Bounds of the Houſe in writing, as <hi>Farr</hi> had directed him: Which <hi>Farr</hi> having received from him, got a Leaſe drawn, at a very low Rent, upon conſideration of a large Fine in the Leaſe, mentioned to have been paid: And you may be ſure, he wanted not for Witneſſes to atteſt it: Demanded ſhortly after Poſſeſſion of the Houſe: At which the Landlord ſeemed to be ſtartled, as knowing of no ſuch Contract, as <hi>Farr</hi> laid claim to: Whereupon <hi>Farr</hi> ſued him; his own Inſtruments ſwore the Leaſe, and the en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſealing and delivery thereof; and the Carpenter ſwore the probable Circumſtances of their Diſcourſe, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> So that <hi>Farr</hi> recover'd Dammages againſt the Landlord; who, by this time, underſtanding what <hi>Farr</hi> was, choſe rather to compound the Buſineſs to his own loſs, than run the hazard of loſing his Houſe, and further miſchief.</p>
            <p>He alſo Cheated one Mr. <hi>Pore,</hi> Cellar-Keeper at the <hi>Kings-Bench,</hi> of Five Pounds, which he borrowed of him; and for his Security, left with him a Tru<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>k of Writings, which he ſaid was of 1000 Pound value, and a Watch. The Old Man ſatisfied with this <hi>Depoſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tum,</hi> bad him lock it up, for he ſhould not deſire to meddle with any thing there; only deſired, He might have his Money again honeſtly; which <hi>Farr</hi> promiſed:
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:103523:13"/>But in locking up the Trunk, ſlip'd out the Watch, leaving only the Writings, which were of no concern or value. <hi>Pore</hi> could not get his Money; therefore re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolved, and brake open the Trunk before Witneſs (and 'tis well he did ſo, otherwiſe <hi>Farr</hi> would have had one fling at him) found no Watch, nor any thing more than waſte Paper: And I conceive he had but a bad bargain, for Five Pound goes a great way in that Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modity.</p>
            <p>And a man would have thought, that <hi>Farr</hi> would not have thus diſobliged One, that was like to be his ſo near Neighbour; but he ſpared none that he could reach.</p>
            <p>For there was one Mr. <hi>Ivy,</hi> of a good Family, and bred a Clerk, and (though at preſent things were not over-plentiful with him) Heir to a good Eſtate in Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſion. This Perſon did <hi>Farr</hi> make uſe of, for moſt of his writing buſineſs (whether he were privy to the ill uſe made of them by <hi>Farr,</hi> I cannot ſay) and there was a great intimacy, and ſeeming friendſhip between them: Yet when he was dead, <hi>Farr,</hi> like an ungrate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Villain, forcibly entered his Houſe, ſeized all the Goods, turn'd the Widow and Children out of Doors: And being afterwards, by Mrs. <hi>Ivyes</hi> Friends, Indicted, produced at his Tryal a forged Bill of Sale, and ſome of his Witneſſes to ſwear it, and ſo was acquitted: But in revenge, arreſted the Widow in feign'd Actions, to a great value, and run her into the Counter, where ſhe continued for ſome time, till bayl'd out by Friends, who knew there was nothing real againſt her.</p>
            <p>There is a common Report about the Town (but I muſt ſay, I cannot find it confirm'd to my ſatisfaction)
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:103523:13"/>That having underſtood, that a Gentleman of his Name, living in <hi>Eſſex,</hi> a Moneyed Man, and a frequent Purchaſer, was now in <hi>London,</hi> upon a Purchaſe, and ſo might be probably thought, to want the ſupply of a little Money, for the preſent Depoſition: He went, in his richeſt habit, with a Foot-Boy at his heels, to a Scri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veners Shop in <hi>Cornhill,</hi> and deſired to ſpeak with the Gentleman; who coming, he with a kind of careleſs and generous frankneſs, told him, That he underſtood he was a Perſon that could ſupply his preſent Occaſions, which required 200 Pound, to make up a greater ſumm, he was to pay; but withall, That he ſhould not give any other Security, than his own Bond. The Scrivener told him, That he did not uſe to lend ſuch a ſumm, but upon better Security, than one ſingle Mans Bond: <hi>Farr</hi> preſently replyed, <hi>Sir, It may be ſo; but I conceive, if you had knowledge of me, you would not ſcruple my ſingle Bond, for a greater matter: My Name is</hi> Farr, <hi>I live in ſuch a Place; if you pleaſe to take the pains to enquire, I will pay the Charge</hi> (throwing him down a Piece of Gold) <hi>and for your Civility, in ſupplying my preſent Convenience, ſhall not be unworthy.</hi> The Scrivener, willing to be get<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting, very officiouſly promiſed, to give him his an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer within three dayes; and the next day rid over to the Place, where he told him he lived; and firſt en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quired of the Inn-keeper, where he ſet up his Horſe; who told him, That Eſquire <hi>Farr</hi> was a very wealthy Man, and moneyed; that he own'd almoſt their whole Town, and was continually purchaſing more; and that he heard, he was upon a great Purchaſe now, and that he was gone to <hi>London.</hi> The Scrivener hearing this Story, ſo agreeable with that <hi>Farr</hi> had told him, was pretty well
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:103523:14"/>ſatisfied; but yet made farther enquiry in the Town, and found them all agreeing, and ſo he came home. On the Day appointed, <hi>Farr</hi> came for the Money, and had it, only upon his own Bond. When the Money be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>came due, the Scrivener went to Eſquire <hi>Farr,</hi> to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand it; but to no other effect, than to find that he was Cheated; and that he was not the Man who had his Money. In ſome ſhort time after, he heard of this <hi>Farr,</hi> and what a kind of Perſon he was; and after a long inquiſition, found him a Priſoner in the <hi>Kings-Bench.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>About the ſame time, he Cheated another Scrivener, on the back-ſide of the <hi>Exchange:</hi> To whom he came, and told him, He had occaſion for 100 Pound; that his Name was <hi>R. Green,</hi> a Merchant, living in ſuch a Place; and for his Security, nominated two other Merchants, <hi>viz.</hi> one Mr. <hi>Williams,</hi> and one Mr. <hi>Rich<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ardſon,</hi> Perſons of good account; and told the Scrivener where they dwelt; and bid him, in his enquiry, be private and modeſt; telling him, That at preſent they were both out of Town (for he had choſen the time of their abſence, as moſt conducing to his Deſign) that he ſhould only ſatisfie himſelf, as to their Capacity; and that himſelf would take care to bring them, when come Town. The Scrivener enquired, and found the two Gentlemen to be beyond queſtion. <hi>Farr,</hi> within three or four dayes, call'd upon him; and had for an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer, That he might have the Money, upon the Secu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity propounded: Whereupon <hi>Farr,</hi> about two dayes after, brought two Perſons (of his own Gang) habit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed like Citizens of good rank, who perſonated Mr. <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liams,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Richardſon;</hi> and as ſuch, they ſealed and
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:103523:14"/>delivered the Bond, together with <hi>Farr,</hi> and had the Money. When the Money became due, the Scrivener hearing nothing of the Principal, went to the Security, who were ſurprized at the thing, knowing nothing of it; and the Scrivener ſoon found that he was Cheated, but could not find by whom; till long after, ſeeing him, as he look'd through the Pillory, againſt the <hi>Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>change, Agnovit Faciem,</hi> he tax'd him with it, but <hi>Farr</hi> denied it; and 'twas hardly worth the Scriveners while, to endeavour to prove it, he being then a Priſoner.</p>
            <p>In the ſame kind did he Cheat a Lady, lodging at Mr. <hi>Appletrees</hi> in <hi>Covent-Garden,</hi> of 50 Pound.</p>
            <p>He alſo Cheated a Country Lace-man, at the <hi>Bull and Mouth</hi> by <hi>Alderſgate,</hi> of near 40 Pounds worth of Lace; which having choſen out, he deſired the Man to goe with him, and he would pay him his Money: So he had him to an Ale-houſe, on the back-ſide of <hi>Black-Horſe-Alley,</hi> by <hi>Fleet-Bridge,</hi> and call'd for a Pot of Drink; telling him, He would goe fetch him his Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney preſently: Took the Lace with him, but return'd no more. The Man found him ſome time after, when he was a Priſoner; and pleading Poverty, got of him Five Pound, for his Forty, and gave him a Diſcharge. And I think he fared better, than moſt that had to do with him.</p>
            <p>He put a handſome Trick upon one in <hi>Barbican,</hi> thus:</p>
            <p>Pretending to goe a Journey into the Country, he pack'd up, in a Trunk, moſt of his beſt Apparel, both Woollen and Linnen; and ſent for a Porter, to carry the Trunk into <hi>Alderſgate-Street,</hi> to the Carriers: When
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:103523:15"/>the Porter came, he bid him take notice of what he put into the Trunk, for fear it ſhould any way miſcarry; which the Porter did: Then he ſent away the Porter, to buy a Cord; and when he was gone, unpack'd the Trunk of the Cloaths, and fill'd it with Raggs, Brick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>batts, and Pieces of Wood, and lock'd it up. The Por<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter returning, corded up the Trunk, and ſo away with it he went, and <hi>Farr</hi> with him. When they came to the Inn, the Carrier of the Place (whither he pretend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed he would have ſent it) was gone out of Town the day before, and would not come again till next Week. He therefore ordered the Porter, to take the Trunk, and goe with him; and ſo he carried it to one whom he knew in <hi>Barbican;</hi> and deſired, That he might leave it there till next Week, that the Carrier came to Town, and then he would come for it; the Man let him leave it. The next Week, <hi>Farr,</hi> taking the ſame Porter, went for the Trunk; but pretended, That he had pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent uſe of ſomething that was in it; and therefore, in preſence of the Porter, opened the Trunk; which being ſo differently fraught, from what the Porter ſaw it fill'd with at firſt, he call'd to the Man of the Houſe, told him, That his Tru<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>k was opened, and his Goods taken away, and that Rubbiſh left in the room; the Porter juſtified the ſame. The Man (as he had good cauſe) pleaded ignorance, but it little availed him; for <hi>Farr</hi> brought his Action againſt him; and by Mrs. <hi>Chadwicks,</hi> and another of his Swearers Oaths, together with the Porter's, recovered againſt the Man 20 Pound, beſides Coſts of Sure.</p>
            <p>In the ſame manner almoſt, he ſerved a Watch-maker, in <hi>Lombard-Street.</hi> He, in company of two
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:103523:15"/>more, whom he brought with him, upon Deſign, left with the Watch-maker, his Watch, to be mended; and within a ſhort time after came for it. The Watch-maker had fixed it, and offered it to him: He told him, That was none of his Watch, deſcribed his to be one of a farr greater value. The Watch-maker being confi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent, that was the Watch he left, would give him no other: Whereupon he ſued the Watch-maker; and brought his two Agents, to ſwear the delivery of ſuch a Watch, as <hi>Farr</hi> claim'd; and ſo recovered treble the value of the Watch.</p>
            <p>He alſo ſhewed a kind of a ſlippery Trick to one Mr. <hi>Boucher:</hi> To whom he brought a Man, that ſold him a Suit of Tapeſtry Hangings, for 15 Pound: A while af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter he brought another Man to him, who laid claim to the Hangings, and ſaid, They were ſtole from him; and that, if he would not deliver them, he would in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dite him. <hi>Farr</hi> alſo told him, That the Perſon of whom he had them, was a Stranger to him, nor did he know how to find him, or where to enquire after him. The Man therefore, for fear of a worſe thing, return'd the Hangings, and loſt his Money; but afterwards un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtood, that the Hangings were really <hi>Farr</hi>'s, who had thus Cheated him.</p>
            <p>A Man would think, that all theſe ſucceſsful Vil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lanies could not but have made him rich; but he was very profuſe in his Expences, and in his Law-Sutes could not be ſparing (for a good Cauſe may be ſtarved, much more will a bad and weak One call for ſtrong ſupport) ſo that it doth appear, that he was but mean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly moneyed: For being worſted in a Suit about his <hi>Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vent-Garden</hi> Houſes, he was ſhopp'd in the <hi>Fleet,</hi> upon
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:103523:16"/>an Execution but of Threeſcore Pound; which he could not, or would not pay, till he found out a Trick to do it by, in this manner.</p>
            <p>It hath been formerly intimated, that he generally practiſed Brokeage between Buyer and Seller; and that very frequently for Goods ſtollen, and indirectly come by. Being therefore now a Priſoner in the <hi>Fleet,</hi> the Parties that had robb'd Mr. <hi>L.</hi> Mercer in <hi>Lombard-Street,</hi> came to him, and deſired him, to diſpoſe of ſuch things for them; he undertook it, and dealt with an Old Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman (a Phyſician) then a Priſoner alſo in the <hi>Fleet,</hi> and a miſerable penurious Man, to lend him 120 Pound upon the Goods, which he did; and the Goods, pack'd up in Hampers, were ſet up in his Chamber, and put under his Bed. <hi>Farr</hi> having finger'd the Money, went to the Warden of the <hi>Fleet,</hi> paid off his Execution, and ſo had his liberty of going abroad. He went to the Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon robb'd, and told him, That he thought, he could do him ſome ſervice towards the recovery of his Goods. <hi>Farr</hi> had a Bond ſeal'd to him, for Thirty Pound, pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able upon the receiving of the Goods. The Mercer, with ſome Friends, went and procured the Lord Chief Juſtice his Warrant, and came, with <hi>Farr,</hi> to a Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vern, hard by the <hi>Fleet. Farr</hi> told them, He would not appear himſelf, but gave them punctual directions to the Chamber; whither they went, with a Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtable (the Warden giving leave) and found the Goods, and ſeized them; So the poor Old Man loſt his Money, and ſoon after his Life for grief: A ſtrange Man, to carry his Life in his Purſe.</p>
            <p>A while after, the Merchants came to call their Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctor to an account for their Money: He told them, He
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:103523:16"/>had no Money, were not the Goods ſeiz'd on? At which they grumbling, he bade them be gone, while they were well, or elſe he would pay them with a Halter.</p>
            <p>This Money (with the 30 Pound of the Mercer, which was duly paid him) ſet him a clear board.</p>
            <p>And now Mounſieur <hi>L.</hi> Mountebank appears upon the Stage afreſh, where his firſt Patient is</p>
            <p>A young Merchant, or whole-ſale Dealer in Stuffs: To whoſe Ware-houſe he went, in a very Gentile ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bit; told the Gentleman, That he was newly come from <hi>Cadiz,</hi> and that he had occaſion for ſome of his Commodities; and that if he had to furniſh him, he ſhould beſtow near 1000 Pound with h im before his departure: but for the preſent, look'd out, and or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der'd to be ſent into his Houſe, about 100 Pounds worth. The Merchant ſent in the Goods, and his Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant with them. When he came to <hi>Farr</hi>'s Houſe, he was conducted into the Dining-Room, which was very compleatly furniſhed, and hung with Tapeſtry. <hi>Farr</hi> comes to him, with his Foot-Boy behind him, whom he preſently, upon fight of the Man, bade goe to his Miſtreſs, for the Key of his Cloſet: The Boy (as in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtructed) brought word, That his Miſtreſs was gone over the Water, to give a viſit to a Lady, whom he na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med: VVhereat <hi>Farr</hi> ſtorm'd, and ſeemed much diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>contented; and after near an hours ſtay, very comple<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentally told the Young Man, He was very ſorry, that he was forced thus to diſapoint him, but he ſaw how it was; and therefore intreated him to come about Eight of the Clock next Morning. The Young Man was very well ſatisfied, and went his way: The next
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:103523:17"/>Morning he came at the hour appointed, but <hi>Farr</hi> would not be ſpoken with, and ſo came three or four Mornings, and loſt his labour; Then the Maſter came, but 'twas all one, no Mr. <hi>Farr</hi> would appear; till, by frequent coming he made a ſhift at length to meet with him at home: He rail'd at him, call'd him Knave, and Cheat, and the like; and told him, He would make him an Example; and away he went for a VVarrant for him. <hi>Farr</hi> thereupon ſent for two of his Friends, who, by his Order, went and fetch'd a VVarrant for the Merchant, with which they ſtaid, till he came with his VVarrant and Conſtable, and then delivered it to the Conſtable, who muſt execute it; and inſtead of carrying <hi>Farr,</hi> carried the Gentleman before a Juſtice; where <hi>Farr</hi>'s two Friends ſwore flat Fellony againſt him, as having taken away ſuch and ſuch Goods out of Mr. <hi>Farr</hi>'s Houſe, upon which he was committed to <hi>Newgate;</hi> whither ſending for Friends, and adviſing with them, he was counſelled (and took their Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſell) to endeavour to make an end; for that it would be dangerous, if the Fellows ſhould come in, and ſwear the ſame at his Tryal, as they had before the Juſtice. So the Gentleman ſent ſome Friends to <hi>Farr,</hi> who con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fidently perſiſted in the ſame Story, as his Friends had ſworn, That the Gentleman had robb'd him, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And the Concluſion was, the Gentleman loſt his Goods, and <hi>Farr</hi> cauſed his Friends to forbear Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecution.</p>
            <p>He had inſinuated himſelf into the acquaintance of Mrs. <hi>Ray,</hi> the Midwife, ſo farr, as that ſhe intruſted him with all her Buſineſs, when living; and when ſhe dyed, left her only Child to his care and tuition, with
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:103523:17"/>what ſhe had to leave him: But <hi>Farr</hi> moſt villanouſly laid claim to all her Goods (which were very good, and the Furniture of her Houſe rich) as his; and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duc'd a forg'd Deed of hers to that purpoſe, and left her Child to the Pariſh.</p>
            <p>He did his endeavour to have Cheated one Mrs. <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon,</hi> an Apothecaries VVidow near the <hi>New-Exhange,</hi> whoſe Husband (when living) he had help'd to the buying of Hangings, and other Upholſtery, for fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhing his Houſe; which Mr. <hi>Wilſon</hi> paid for, in a ſhort time after the delivery; But after he was dead, <hi>Farr</hi> came to the VVidow, and told her, He had a Bond of her Husbands of Threeſcore Pound, and that there was Thirty Pound of it unpaid. The Woman knew that her Husband had diſcharged that Debt long agoe, and therefore refuſed to pay him: Whereupon he ſued her, and put her to a great deal of Charges, and would without doubt have made her pay it (for he had forged a Bond) but that the Gentleman, who ſollicited her Buſineſs, underſtanding what <hi>Farr</hi> was, had ſcrap'd together ſo many of his Rogueries, which he would have produced at the Tryal, and the Buſineſs of the Pil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lory, for Forgery, did then, in the very Nick, fall upon him, that he forbare farther proſecution for the preſent: And I conceive the Gentlewoman is now out of his reach.</p>
            <p>One Mr. <hi>Labbey,</hi> a <hi>French-man</hi> (now his Majeſty's Shooemaker) did formerly (as Fore-man, or chief Journey-man) manage the Trade for a Woman, whoſe Husband was gone into <hi>Turkey.</hi> The Woman wanting Money to carry on her Buſineſs, was ſupplyed by <hi>Farr</hi> with Nine Pound, upon her own, Mr. <hi>Labbey</hi>'s,
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:103523:18"/>and Mr. <hi>Labbey</hi>'s Friend's Bond, for payment of Ten Pound at three Months end. Before the expiration of which time, the Woman, and Mr. <hi>Labbey,</hi> went into <hi>Holland,</hi> and there ſtayed about a Year. When the Money was due, <hi>Farr</hi> (knowing he had now a fit ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject and time for his Knavery) went to the third Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, who was Security, and demanded the Money. The Man unwilling (as he ſaid) to pay Ten Pound, for which he never ſo much as drank, deſired him to continue the Money, till the Principal ſhould return, which would be in a ſhort time. <hi>Farr</hi> was preſently at his <hi>Quid dabis?</hi> Two Angells appeared, and for that time removed him; but his Viſits afterwards, in this kind, were ſo frequent (alwayes ſhaking the Rod over the poor man's back, in caſe he began to be hide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bound) that in the three Quarters of a Year, that he forbare him, he drew from him as much as the Principal Money came to; and at laſt arreſted him, and put him to a great deal of Charge: And though the Man would have paid the Principal Money, yet <hi>Farr</hi> (finding him an eaſie and unskillful man) would not make an end, under the forfeiture of the Bond, which was Twenty Pound. Hereupon the Man writ a pittiful Letter to Mr. <hi>Labbey,</hi> who, upon receipt thereof, came over. So ſoon as <hi>Farr</hi> heard of it, he arreſted him, kept him, till he made him pay what Fees the Officers would ask, and gave new Bond, with other Security, for payment of 15 Pound within three months. Three dayes before the money was due, <hi>Farr</hi> came to Mr. <hi>Labbey,</hi> and told him, That the money would be due on ſuch a Day: Mr. <hi>Labbey</hi> told him, He hop'd to be ready for him at the time, having moſt of it by him. <hi>Farr</hi> (finding too much
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:103523:18"/>meat upon the bone to be laid aſide ſo) deſired to drink with him: Mr. <hi>Labbey</hi> went with him: <hi>Farr</hi> ask'd, If he had a Pair of Shooes that would fit him: Mr. <hi>Labbey</hi> fetch'd him a Pair, but they were much too bigg; yet <hi>Farr</hi> took them, ſaying, He lov'd to goe eaſie in his feet; and told Mr. <hi>Labbey,</hi> He would have them Shooes, and would give him three weeks or a month after the time, for payment of the money; which Mr. <hi>Labbey</hi> with thanks accepted (but if this had not been voluntarily offer'd, could and would have paid in the money on the day) But the very day after the money was due, Mr. <hi>Labbey,</hi> and his two Securityes, were arreſted; then <hi>Farr</hi> came to them, and would have tamper'd, to have added the other Five Pound for Charges, and ſo have made it 20 Pound, and conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nued it. But Mr. <hi>Labbey</hi> had too much of him already, and with what he had by him, and help of ſome Friends, made a ſhift to get rid of this Knave, by paying even what he pleaſed to demand: So that this Nine Pound, did in a Year and Quarters time, ſwell to at leaſt 50 Pound. <hi>Farr</hi> having thus ſhorn him cloſe, almoſt to the skin, lets him run, not out of any kindneſs, but only that he might ſeize him again, when his fleece was new grown: And that this was his intent is clear; for not long agoe meeting him, he asked him of his health, and enquired of the Woman his former Miſtreſs; and being anſwered ſlightingly, he told him, He had not done with him yet, for he had a Bond of his for Forty Pound, which he had lent her, and that he muſt pay it: At which Mr. <hi>Labbey</hi> was much ſtartled, fearing a Trick. And doubtleſs he had had it upon him, but that very ſuddenly thereupon, he was ſworn his
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:103523:19"/>Majeſty'd Shooemaker, and ſo <hi>Farr</hi> durſt not arreſt him. But Mr. <hi>Labbey</hi> could not think himſelf ſafe, till he ſaw him hang'd, and put up into his Coffin; ſo great a dread had his Villanies imoreſs'd upon him.</p>
            <p>While he was a Priſoner in the <hi>Fleet,</hi> at the Sute of one Mr. <hi>Chambers,</hi> of whom we ſhall have further oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſion to ſpeak hereafter, he played a moſt treacherous part, to one of his acquaintance, and fellow-Priſoner, Mr. <hi>Wotton:</hi> Who having ſome Goods, lying in a Place, where he feared they were not very ſafe, told <hi>Farr</hi> of it, (who could goe abroad, but this <hi>Wotton</hi> could not) <hi>Farr</hi> thereupon told him, That he would (if he pleaſed) remove them to his Houſe, and there he ſhould have the uſe of a Room, to lay them in; which <hi>Wotton</hi> accepted of, and thanked him. So <hi>Farr</hi> went and took all his Goods, and ſold them, putting the money into his own Pocket, and brought with him to <hi>Wotton</hi> a Key, as of the Door where the Goods were lock'd up; but that Key was all that <hi>Wotton</hi> could ever get for all his Goods.</p>
            <p>Now alſo was it, when one <hi>Diamond</hi> a Weaver in <hi>Spittle-fields</hi> having ſerved him with ſome Proceſs out of Chancery, at the Sute of Mr. <hi>Alexander</hi> formerly men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned, he in revenge got a Warrant to ſearch his Houſe for ſtoln goods, and taking a Conſtable with him, broke open his doors, and under pretence of ſearching in the Bed, clapt his own Watch between the Sheets, and a while after, upon a more exact ſearch found it there, and thereupon took the Man out of his houſe, had him before a Juſtice, ſwore felony againſt him, and got him committed to <hi>Newgate,</hi> where the poor man was clapt into Irons, and ſo lay all night: but the next morning ſome friends of his went to the Iuſtice,
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:103523:19"/>and informed him of the whole buſineſs, who there up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on took Bail for him, and the next Seſſions, <hi>Farr</hi> not proſecuting, he was diſcharged.</p>
            <p>About this time alſo did he moſt brutiſhly ruine a young man, whoſe name was <hi>John Chambers,</hi> by Trade a Grocer, who having been arreſted and thrown into the Counter, had taken of all the things that were then brought againſt him, only there ſtood enter'd in the Book againſt <hi>John Chambers,</hi> (not this man, but the Silk-throſter, <hi>Farrs</hi> great Antagoniſt) and Action of 500 <hi>l.</hi> at <hi>Farrs</hi> ſute: This young man therefore ſent for <hi>Farr,</hi> and deſired him to certifie that he was not the perſon, that ſo he might be diſcharged: <hi>Farr</hi> private<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, when no body was in preſence, would confeſs that he was not the man, but would not doe it before any witneſs, unleſs the man would give him 10 <hi>l.</hi> which ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther than doe, he turn'd himſelf over a Priſoner to the Kings Bench, which was his utter undoing.</p>
            <p>Then alſo did he by his friend <hi>Chadw.</hi> lay a bait for a Gudgeon that bit, and was upon the hook, but proved not to be worth the catching. <hi>Chadwick</hi> had told a young man (he was acquainted with) that he could help him to 50 <hi>l.</hi> upon ſecurity, which the young man propound<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and the other accepted: <hi>Farr</hi> (then a priſoner in the <hi>Fleet</hi>) was the man that ſhould lend the money. At a time agreed on, the principal, with his two friends came to the <hi>Fleet; Farr</hi> told them, that being a Priſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner he would not have it known that he had any money, (for that he ſhould never be free then from borrowers) bad them go to an Ale-houſe in <hi>Fleet-yard,</hi> and he would come to them: They did ſo, he followed, and then told them, that he expected the money to have been
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:103523:20"/>brought before that time, but 'twas not yet come; however, ſince they were all there together, he ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſed them to ſeal the Bond, and let the Principal keep it till to morrow, and then, if he came, he ſhould not miſs of the money: This was done, and ſo they part<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed for that Night: The next morning the man came accordingly; <hi>Farr</hi> deſired him, to goe to the Place they were at the laſt Night; he, with two of his Beagles, whom he had gotten ready, followed; they fell to talk and diſcourſe, making no mention of the money; till at length the man deſired <hi>Farr</hi> to diſpatch him: <hi>Farr</hi> prayed him to let him ſee the Bond; which having finger'd, he clap'd it up into his Pocket, and went his way: The man followed him, but could obtain nothing but ill words. This Bond had certainly been put in ſure ſome time after, but that both Principal and Security prov'd leaky Veſſels, and ſunk before they came to be boarded.</p>
            <p>Nor was his Roguery confin'd to <hi>England</hi> only; for one Mr. <hi>Marlow,</hi> whom, by continual Vexations, he had almoſt ruin'd, did, to preſerve himſelf, goe with his Family, to live in <hi>Virginia,</hi> where he had the good hap to thrive, and grow wealthy: Which <hi>Farr</hi> hearing, he forged a Bond of his for 50 Pound, came to a publick Notary, and had it certified under his hand; and by proving it by the Oaths of two of his Creatures, before the Lord Mayor, had it avouched by the City Seal. This he ſent over, by one Mr. <hi>Guyard,</hi> Maſter of a Ship, bound for <hi>Virginia;</hi> who knowing nothing, but that the Bond was real, and the Debt juſtly due, did, accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to his truſt, ſue the ſaid <hi>Marlow,</hi> and recover of him the ſaid ſumm of money. But ſo great was the out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cry
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:103523:20"/>againſt him by the Planters, that he durſt not come on ſhore afterward, for fear of miſchief. And the Brother of this <hi>Marlow,</hi> ſometime after coming for <hi>England,</hi> found out <hi>Farr,</hi> and ran him through the arm: He thought (be-like.) he was too much a Rogue, for him to run the hazard of being hang'd for him.</p>
            <p>He once borrowed of Mr. <hi>T. P.</hi> a great Uſurer, 80. Pound, and being (when the money was due) ſued for it, he, by the Oath of <hi>Chad.</hi> and another, proved the money paid, and the Bond ſatisfied.</p>
            <p>Having gone thus far without any remarkable check or controul, at leaſt any ſuch as might ſeem to bear a proportion with the wrongs and injuries which he had done, I am perſwaded he began to think, that nothing was either diſhoneſt or difficult that had profit at the end of it; and in this perſwaſion fell upon a young Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>woman, into whoſe acquaintance (and ſome know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge of her affairs) he had ſcrued himſelf by means of his Mrs. <hi>Chadwick,</hi> and whom, being a Widow, young, unacquainted, and (as he thought) un-allyed in the City, he pitch't upon as likely to fall an eaſie Prey to his ravenous deſires. Her husband was (living) Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain of a Ship, and left her in good condition, about 500 <hi>l.</hi> of money in her Purſe, and above that value in Goods, Jewels, Rings, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> She lodged (when he firſt came to be acquainted with her) near <hi>New-Market,</hi> li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving upon the uſe of her Money, the diſpoſal of which ſhe intruſted to a friend, upon whoſe death <hi>Farr</hi> would have ſucceeded in that imployment, but the young Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlewoman did not like him ſo well, as to truſt him with that commodity. He (ſeeing his game before him) preſs'd forward towards a nearer acquaintance; ſhe
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:103523:21"/>(for fear of him, of whoſe pranks ſhe had heard ſome whiſpers) as induſtiouſly ſhunning it; inſomuch that ſhe reſolved, and did remove her lodging. He had his Spies upon her, who obſerved amongſt other things a large and heavy Trunk to be removed; and ſince ſhe would not come to hand, he reſolved to try another way, laying his foundation upon this Trunk.</p>
            <p>Having found our her new Lodging, he took out a Warrant againſt her, and being apprehended, carryed her before a Iuſtice, ſwearing againſt her, <hi>that ſhe had feloniouſly ſtoln out of ſuch a houſe (her former Lodging) a Trunk worth</hi> 500 <hi>l.</hi>
               <hi>belonging to him:</hi> whereupon ſhe was committed. She thereupon ſent to a Brother-in-law of hers, one Mr. <hi>Betts</hi> a Broad-weaver in <hi>Spittle-fields,</hi> who intreating the company of his Friend and Neighbour Mr <hi>Chambers,</hi> they went to the Iuſtice, and informing him of the truth of the matter, prevailed with him to accept of Bail, ſo they bailed her. <hi>Farr</hi> proſecuted her by way of Indictment upon a Treſpaſs, at <hi>Hicks</hi>'s Hall, where the Trunk being produced in Court, and ſhe proving her property to it, and the goods within it, the Court ordered them to be re-delivered her. Upon this, <hi>Farr</hi> (though the Gentlewoman owed him nothing) upon pretence of a Debt, reſolv'd to lay an Attachment upon the Trunk, as they were carrying it away; and to this purpoſe, had his Officers ready at the Hall-Gate. This being underſtood by the Gentlewomans Friends, they procured another Trunk, as like the real one, both in ſize and ſhape, as they could get, and conveyed it into the Houſe, by a back-Door; where they filled it with Raggs, Straw, Brick-batts, and ſuch like Lumber; and for garniſh, put in a Pair
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:103523:21"/>of Hornes, and a Rope and Butter; corded it up, and ſent it out by a Porter. <hi>Farr</hi> ſtanding ready, with his Officers, ſeized the Trunk, laying his Attachmnet on it; ſo it was depoſited into the hands of an Officer be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longing to the Court, till Judgement ſhould be paſſed upon it; which (no defence being made by the other ſide) was ſoon obtained; and then the Trunk was open<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed: A goodly ſight to ſee. The real Trunk was at Night conveyed a way in a Coach.</p>
            <p>This Diſappointment, with the Affront in the man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner of it, ſo deſperately enraged <hi>Farr,</hi> that he let fly freely at them all; and firſt for Mr. <hi>Chambers,</hi> whoſe youthful and ſprightly activity, he thought to have been chiefly inſtrumental in this Affair. And as Mr. <hi>Chambers</hi> hath cauſe enough to wiſh, he had never ſeen <hi>Farr</hi>'s face; ſo had <hi>Farr</hi> no cauſe of triumph over Mr. <hi>Chambers:</hi> For though this laſt Prank againſt Mrs. <hi>Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neir</hi> hang'd him, yet was he finely prepared and fitted for it, by Mr. <hi>Chambers.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And firſt he arreſted Mr. <hi>Chambers,</hi> and ſued him, in the Name of one <hi>George Farebanck,</hi> for 80 Pieces of Gold, pretended to be left in the hands of Mr. <hi>Chambers,</hi> by the ſaid <hi>Farebanck,</hi> as his Security, for being Bayl for Mrs. <hi>Reynolds.</hi> This (though Mr. <hi>Chambers</hi> neither knew the man, not to his knowledge ever-ſaw him, or had one Penny-left with him, upon that account, by a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny one whatſoever) was ſworn by <hi>Farr, Chadwick,</hi> and his Wife; and Mr. <hi>Chambers</hi> caſt in 90 Pound, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides Coſts of Sute, and was forced to pay it every farthing.</p>
            <p>Then he brought an Action of <hi>Trover</hi> againſt him in the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> for the Trunk, and 1000 Pounds worth
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:103523:22"/>of Goods in it, at the Sute of the ſaid <hi>Farebanck.</hi> The two <hi>Chadwicks</hi> ſwore, his having confeſſed, That he had once the Trunk in his Poſſeſſion: Whereupon Mr. <hi>Chambers,</hi> not denying it, pleaded Juſtification, and proved the right and propriety to the Trunk and Goods, to be in Mrs. <hi>Reynolds,</hi> by 65 Witneſſes; and ſo the Verdict went for him, againſt the Plantiff.</p>
            <p>Next he ſued him, by Bill of <hi>Mid.</hi> upon a forged Bond of 300 Pound. The Witneſſes were <hi>H. Smith, T. Sandys,</hi> and <hi>L. Liſt.</hi> At the Tryal, <hi>Chambers</hi> proved, by the Keepers of <hi>Newgate,</hi> that <hi>Smith</hi> had been convi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted for Fellony; and that <hi>Sandys</hi> had been a Priſoner there: He alſo prov'd, That he never had had any Deal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings with <hi>Farr;</hi> So that the Witneſſes being look'd upon as inſufficient, and the Circumſtances looking ſtrongly towards Forgery, the Jury found now alſo for the Defendant. The like did they afterwards, when he was ſued, upon a forged Bond, for 500 Pound: To which were Witneſſes, <hi>Chadwick,</hi> his wife, and <hi>Sandys.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Mr. <hi>Chambers</hi> encouraged by theſe Succeſſes, and finding thereby, that his Adverſary was mortal; and having hit him in the very Vitalls (by invalidating the teſtimony of his Swearers) ſet upon him in the Offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſive, and brought his Action of 500 Pound againſt him, for wrongs and injuries done to him (for <hi>Farr</hi> had omitted no means whereby to undoe him) He alſo in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duſtriouſly and diligently made enquiry into the manner of his paſs'd Life, and made re-ſearch into the nature and quality of thoſe Perſons he uſed for his Witneſſes; and thus provided, brought his Buſineſs to Tryal, and obtained a Verdict for 400 and odd Pounds. Then
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:103523:22"/>
               <hi>Farr</hi> (upon his own, Mrs. <hi>Chadwicks,</hi> and <hi>Smith</hi>'s Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fidavit, That he had not ſufficient notice of the Tryal) moved for a ſecond Tryal, which was granted, and he thereupon caſt, as in the former. Then he moved (upon many Affidavits, That he was ſurprized, and his Witneſſes not ready) for a third Tryal, but could not obtain it; ſo Judgement was entered up: But he had a Salvo for that, for he forged a Releaſe, under the hand and Seal of Mr. <hi>Chambers,</hi> which coſt much time and charge to diſprove, but at laſt 'twas done, and ſo the Judgement confirmed.</p>
            <p>Therefore, to counterpoiſe this Judgement, he ſets up a new Engine, by forging a Warrant of Attor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, to confeſs Judgement for 300 Pound. And this being a matter of ſo great danger; and a thing, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by an evil-minded Rogue may undoe an honeſt Man, before he is aware of him: And this very Particular, having been prevented, not without extreme diligence, and indefatigable induſtry, when 'twas then upon the brink of Execution; It being alſo full of delightful and uſeful variety, through the whole menage of it; And laſtly, the very Buſineſs that brought him to the Pil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lory, and made his Followers and Partakers uſe their Heels, to ſave their Ears; I ſhall give you as full and particular account thereof, as the deſigned brevity of this Diſcourſe will allow.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Farr</hi> brought with him one (who ſaid his Name was <hi>John Chambers</hi>) to Mr. <hi>Smith,</hi> a Scrivener in <hi>Sea-Cole-Lane;</hi> and deſired to have a Warrant of Attorney, for a Judgement for 300 Pound, from the ſaid <hi>John Cham<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers,</hi> to <hi>Richard Farr,</hi> drawn up: Mr. <hi>Smith</hi> drew it, and the pretended <hi>John Chambers</hi> ſealed and delivered it;
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:103523:23"/>It was witneſſed by Mr. <hi>Smith</hi>'s Man, <hi>T. Lane,</hi> and two others; The Judgement was confeſs'd by one Mr. <hi>Birch,</hi> and enter'd by one Mr. <hi>Leyton,</hi> of the <hi>Common-Pleas?</hi> Execution was made out, and carried to the Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice for Seal; Mr. <hi>Woodruff,</hi> one of the Clerks of the Office, knowing Mr. <hi>Chambers,</hi> and ſo much of the Buſineſs between him and <hi>Farr,</hi> as that 'twas moſt un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>likely (almoſt impoſſible) that <hi>Chambers</hi> could owe him any Money, at leaſt ſuch a ſumm, ſent to <hi>Chambers;</hi> who coming, ſaw his danger, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore went to work to prevent it. By the Writ he found out who was the Attorney, and with him ſaw the Warrant, and thereby the Witneſſes Names, and the Scrivener (as indeed the Attorney, that enter'd up the Judgement, had done before, for his own ſatisfa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction, which he had from the Scriveners Man, who told him, That he ſaw <hi>Jo. Chambers</hi> ſign, ſeal and deliver) <hi>Chambers,</hi> with ſome Friends and Neighbours, who came to be aſſiſtant to him in this Exigence, went to the <hi>Fountain-Tavern</hi> without <hi>Newgate</hi> (having prevailed with Mr. <hi>Birch,</hi> and Mr. <hi>Leyton,</hi> the aforeſaid Attor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys, to place themſelves in a Room next adjoyning, that they might hear the diſcourſe, and ſo be fully in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed) Mr. <hi>Chambers</hi> went for the Scrivener, and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſired, That he would bring his Man with him, for that there was ſome Buſineſs to be done, that would require both their preſence; ſo they went both: When they came, after ſalu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ation, and ſome little diſcourſe, one of Mr. <hi>Chambers</hi> Friends ask'd the Scriveners Man, Whether he knew one Mr. <hi>Chambers?</hi> He ſaid <hi>Yes:</hi> They ask'd him, <hi>How long?</hi> He ſaid, <hi>His first knowledge was about a Month agoe, for then he was there, and ſealed a Wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:103523:23"/>to Mr.</hi> Farr: They ask'd him, Whether he could know him again, when he ſaw him? He anſwer'd, <hi>He thought he ſhould:</hi> Then they ask'd him, What kind of Man he was? He deſcribed one very tall, light brown hair, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in all Particulars quite different from Mr. <hi>Chambers:</hi> Being ask'd, Which of the Company was moſt likely to be the Man? He anſwer'd, <hi>There was none tall enough:</hi> It being then told him, That Mr. <hi>Chambers</hi> was the Man: He anſwer'd, <hi>That could not be, for he was moſt unlike him, of any in the Room.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Attorneys herewith ſatisfied, went with Mr. <hi>Chambers</hi> to the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Bridgeman;</hi> who, upon hearing Mr. <hi>Chambers</hi> Complaint, told them, That he ſhould not command them to forbear Executi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, but (if they would take his advice) he thought it moſt ſafe for them, That when Mrs. <hi>Chadwick,</hi> who ſollicited the Buſineſs (for <hi>Farr</hi> was now a Priſoner in the <hi>Fleet</hi>) came to them for the Execution, they would do well to apprehend her, that ſo full enquiry might be made into a matter of ſo dangerous conſequence, and evil preſident. Which Advice, the Attorney con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern'd, followed, ſeized Mrs. <hi>Chadw.</hi> when ſhe came, carried her before a Juſtice, by whom ſhe was commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to <hi>Newgate. Farr,</hi> by frequent Meſſengers, impor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuned the Attorney for his Execution; threatning (in caſe of refuſal) to ſue him for the Debt. Whereupon Mr. <hi>Chambers,</hi> at the deſire of the Attorney (who did not deſire to fall under the hands of ſo dangerous a Fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low) be ſought his Lordſhip, to vouchſafe a hearing of the Cauſe, privately in his own Chamber: My Lord granted it, and ſent a Tipſtaff for <hi>Farr,</hi> from the <hi>Fleet:</hi> His Lordſhip ask'd <hi>Farr,</hi> Whether he would conſent to
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:103523:24"/>have the Buſineſs heard before him there: <hi>Farr</hi> pretend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, He was not prepared (his Witneſſes being ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent) at the preſent: His Lordſhip ask'd him, If that <hi>Chambers</hi> were the Perſon intended in the Judgement: <hi>Farr</hi> deſired his Lordſhip's excuſe, giving him a reaſon why he could not do it without prejudice: Whereupon his Lordſhip told him, He had known many Debtors aſhamed of their Creditors, but never before a Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor aſhamed of his Debtor: So they were diſmiſs'd, and the Buſineſs referr'd to Term. About three or four dayes before Term, <hi>Farr</hi> came to his Lordſhip's Chamber, with three or four Affidavits, deſiring to have his Witneſſes ſworn: His Lordſhip reading the Affidavits, and finding Cauſe to ſuſpect, what upon Tryal he found true, refuſed to ſwear them: So they went to ſome other Juſtice, and were ſworn. Two dayes after, <hi>Chambers</hi> waited on his Lordſhip, with an Affidavit, to which his Lordſhip ſwore him; ſetting forth, That he never had any Concern with <hi>Farr,</hi> ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver receiv'd or had any Money from him, nor owed him a farthing; prayed a day for hearing, and that Evidence might be given <hi>Viva Voce,</hi> not by Affidavit. On the firſt day of the Term, Sir <hi>William Wild</hi> made the motion for <hi>Chambers,</hi> adding ſomething of his own knowledge concerning <hi>Farr:</hi> His Lordſhip thereupon appointed a day, wherein he would be at leiſure to ſearch into the bottom of the Buſineſs. On the day ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, <hi>Farr</hi> appeared, with the Affidavits of all his Witneſſes (whom he had lodged hard by, and upon refuſal of his Affidavits, did produce) They were Mr. <hi>Smith</hi> the Scrivener, his Man <hi>T. Lane,</hi> Mr. and Mrs <hi>Chadwick, Leonard Liſt, T. Sandys, T. Lilly, J.
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:103523:24"/>Fimis,</hi> and ſome others: <hi>Chambers</hi> had many Witneſſes there alſo, amongſt the reſt, ſome of the Under-Keepers of <hi>Newgate,</hi> to teſtifie what they knew of <hi>Farr,</hi> and moſt of his Witneſſes. Upon opening of the Caſe for <hi>Chambers,</hi> by (then Serjeant, now) Judge <hi>Keel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing,</hi> and a ſhort Reply of <hi>Farr</hi>'s Council, his Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip took the Breviats of both ſides, and fell to Exami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation of the Witneſſes, beginning with the Scriveners Man, whom he called out from the reſt of the Gang: He ſwore modeſtly and indifferently what he knew, whereby a ſhrewd gueſs might be made, how the Buſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs was contrived: His Maſter could not ſwear any thing to the purpoſe on either ſide. The reſt ſwore to a hairs breadth, only <hi>Sandys</hi> blunder'd into a Contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diction; and I told you before of the Keepers of <hi>Newgate</hi> being in Court. When it came to be enquir'd, How this Money came to be owing? <hi>Farr</hi> ſaid, 100 Pound lent, and 50 Pound promiſed, to take off him from witneſſing againſt <hi>Chambers,</hi> in a Cauſe in the <hi>Exchequer:</hi> This was ſworn by Mrs. <hi>Chadwick,</hi> and another; but his Lordſhip trapp'd them in the Circumſtances; and by the teſtimony of <hi>Chambers</hi> Witneſſes, and his own Oath (then adminiſter'd) found out the whole Vil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lany, annull'd the Judgement, ordered <hi>Chambers</hi> to enter into Recognizance of 300 Pound, to proſecute <hi>Farr,</hi> at the <hi>Kings-Bench,</hi> for Forgery, next Term: And that the Matter (being ſo foul) ſhould be ſpeci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally recommended to the Lord Chief Juſtice of that <hi>Bench. Chambers</hi> indicted him: <hi>Farr</hi> demurred, his Demurrer was over-ruled, and Judgement paſs'd a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt him, to ſtand in the Pillory (with a Paper, containing his Crime, on his head) in <hi>Westminster</hi>
               <pb n="46" facs="tcp:103523:25"/>Pallace-Yard, and at the <hi>Old-Exchange,</hi> which was accordingly executed.</p>
            <p>Whilſt he ſtood at the <hi>Exchange,</hi> he ſaw <hi>Chambers</hi> looking on him, and therepon pull'd out a <hi>Latitat</hi> (which he had purpoſely provided, to remove him out of his ſight) threw it to an Officer, and bade him ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſt <hi>Chambers,</hi> which he did; but he (knowing <hi>Farr</hi>'s Mrs. <hi>Chadwick</hi> went, and entered an Action of 500. Pound, to which he alſo put in Bayl, and return'd. then Mrs. <hi>Chad.</hi> fetch'd a Warrant for him, and three or four more of his Friends there preſent, whom ſhe knew, and ſaw rejoycing, had them all before a Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice, and ſwore the Peace againſt them: By which a Man may ſee of what a ſhrewd Spirit they both were, and how ready witted ſhe was at her buſineſs.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Chambers</hi> proceeded to proſecute his Witneſſes, and convicted 11 of them, ſome of Forgery, ſome of Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jury, and one of Barratry; and by this ſo weakened him, that as he had his belly full of him, ſo he had but little ſtomack to attempt any thing elſe of moment upon others; lying cloſe, till time and privacy ſhould wear out the memory of theſe miſcarriages: But for preſent ſubſiſtence, and to keep his hand in ure, he did play ſome petty Pranks, which I ſhall relate; only firſt tell you, that a little before this great Tryal with <hi>Chambers,</hi> he twice indicted the fore-mentioned Mrs. <hi>Reynolds,</hi> once for Felony, another time for Treſpaſs, and this laſt had laid ſo firmly, as doubtleſs to have hit her, had not an eminent Citizen (accidentally preſent in this Court) upon hearing the Evidence, voluntarily offered to be ſworn in the Caſe, for that he feared there
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:103523:25"/>was foul Play; and being ſworn, related, how being upon Buſineſs in <hi>Guild-Hall,</hi> he heard the whole Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trivance of this Affair, and did verily believe, that he then ſaw ſome of thoſe faces (pointing to the Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſes) amongſt them. The credit of this Witneſs, and the ſlender account that could be had of the other, prevail'd with the Jury to acquit her.</p>
            <p>And having heard, that Mr. <hi>Betts,</hi> Brother in Law to this Mrs. <hi>Reynolds,</hi> had a Friend beyond Sea, who had left with him a Trunk of wearing Apparel, and other things; he learn'd the Man's Name, and forg'd a Bond to himſelf, from the Perſon, for 20 Pound (though the Man were an abſolute Stranger to him, and never had a Penny Concernment with him in his Life) and then attach'd the Goods in his hands. Mr. <hi>Betts</hi> thought it not his Concern, to ſpend money, in defending ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Man's Sute, and therefore, without Oppoſition, let him proceed to Condemnation. When he came to look over the Goods, he pretended, That the Cloaths had been worn, and the other Goods imbezzled and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trimented, and ſo would not take the Goods <hi>in ſpecie,</hi> but demanded the Money they were appraiſed at, which was (by <hi>Chad.</hi> and another of his Companions) 25 Pound. The Man, little imagining himſelf in any danger, other than to deliver the Goods, never looks after him: So <hi>Farr,</hi> by help of the two Mens Oaths, obtains Judgement againſt him for 25 Pound, takes him in Execution, runs him into the <hi>Counter,</hi> and forces him to pay down 25 Pound into Court. <hi>Farr</hi> was ſo civil, as to take out but 20 Pound, which was his (pretended). Debt, leaving Five Pound in Court, which afterwards, the Man that own'd the Goods had
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:103523:26"/>paid to him: But Mr. <hi>Betts</hi> could never get any part of the Money back again.</p>
            <p>And, that a Man may ſee, that his Condition alter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed not his Nature; being arreſted, by one Mr. <hi>Williams,</hi> a Bayliff, at Mr. <hi>Chambers</hi> Sure, becauſe Mr. <hi>Williams</hi> would not take ſuch Bayl, as he would have him; he; and Mrs. <hi>Chad.</hi> ſwore Fellony againſt him, <hi>viz.</hi> That he had pick'd his Pocket of Three Pound: He alſo com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plained to the Knight Marſhal (and made Affidavit of it) That <hi>Williams</hi> had taken Five Pound of him, for one dayes attendance; both Lyes, and both ſo proved.</p>
            <p>But being now a Priſoner to the <hi>Kings-Bench,</hi> and his buſineſs but little, one Eſquire <hi>Ba.</hi> ſometimes of <hi>Grayes-Inn,</hi> now a Priſoner, intruſted <hi>Farr</hi> to do his petty Buſineſſes abroad, as receiving and paying ſmall ſumms of Money, wherein he was punctual and true (a ſmall Balt he would not bite at) But at length, being intruſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the Gentleman, to goe and borrow ſome Money, upon a Diamond Ring, which the Gentleman account<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed worth 50 Pound; he brought the Gentleman only Four Pound, and ſaid, He could get no more upon it: This ſupplying the Gentleman's preſent Occaſion, he was contented; but having often deſired, to have the Ring redeemed, could never to this day retrive it; nor would <hi>Farr</hi> confeſs where it was; but without doubt he had ſold it, to its value, and put the Money into his Pocket. The ſame Trick he ſerv'd him in another Diamond Ring, valued at 200 Pound, but dipt only for 20. Pound. <hi>Farr</hi> told him, A Friend of his would lend him the ſame Money upon it, at common Intereſt, not at the Brokers rate, which would be ſomething ſav'd in
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:103523:26"/>the Year: The Gentleman prayed him to do it: So he fetch'd the Ring from where it was, but the Gentleman could never hear of it afterwards.</p>
            <p>But the ſlyeſt Trick of all was this: The Gentleman keeping his Chamber in <hi>Grayes-Inn, Farr</hi> came and told him, That the Door was broke open, and ſtood ſo: The Gentleman prayed him to ſee that the Goods in it were ſafe, and to put a Padlock on the Door: Hereupon <hi>Farr</hi> did indeed open the Door, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moved all the Goods, Hangings, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and ſold them, and put a Padlock upon the Door, as he had order, carrying the Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman a falſe Key to it. When <hi>Farr</hi> was convicted, the Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman ſent to him about his Rings, but could get nothing of him, but that he would tell him: Nay, he had a Note ſent him about them under the Gallowes, juſt before his Death, but would not give any ſatisfactory anſwer. Hereupon the Gentleman ſent to have his Chamber opened, but found the Key falſe to the Lock, ſo they broke open the Door, but found nothing but the bare VValls.</p>
            <p>Theſe Rings and Goods (I queſtion not) ſtock't him, and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>abled him to creep again into the World, and to take up his old imployment with his former confidence: for now having liberty of going abroad, gotten money into his Purſe, and the mark of the Pillory almoſt worn out, he had credit enough to put a ſhrewd crick upon one Mr. <hi>Jay</hi> a <hi>Corniſh</hi> man, his fellow Priſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner in the <hi>Kings-Bench,</hi> who wanting friends in the City to be ſecurity for him to goe abroad, <hi>Farr</hi> told him, that if he would give him counter ſecurity, he would procure him two ſubſtanti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al Citizens, upon whoſe ſecurity, he ſhould have liberty. They agreed upon a Judgement with Defeizance upon <hi>Jay</hi>'s eſtate, which is about 50 <hi>l.</hi>
               <hi>per annum. Farr</hi> got the writings drawn, the Gentleman read it, and it lik'd him very well. When he came to ſeal, <hi>Farr</hi> by a trick chang'd this Judgement with Defeizance for one abſolute of the ſame ſize and form. The Gentleman ſatisfi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed with his firſt reading it, Signed, and ſealed, and delivered, And had not <hi>Farrs</hi> troubles faln upon him, <hi>Jay</hi> had before this time found the effects of his unwarineſs; for <hi>Farr</hi> would in a ſhort time have leavyed it upon is Eſtate.</p>
            <pb n="50" facs="tcp:103523:27"/>
            <p>And now on went the beſt Cloaths again, and in them, with a a long Perriwig, a Band with a Lace on't worth 20 <hi>l.</hi> and a Muff, he came to a Gentlewoman living near <hi>Shooe-lane,</hi> who had a Houſe that ſtood in <hi>Fetter-lane</hi> to be let, and agreed with her for the Houſe for 5 years, paying 16 <hi>l.</hi> or thereabouts, <hi>per annum:</hi> Then he ſet Workmen to work made great ſtone ſteps at the door, pull'd down the old Doors and Windows, after the modern mode, putting up larger and higher new Doors, with a large oval win<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dow below, laid the Hearths above ſtairs with marble, putting up ſtately Chimney pieces, and in all things made it fit for the en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tertainment of any perſon of quality, but the poor Workmen (who thought him by his garb to be ſome great perſon, when in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deed a Priſoner in the Kings Bench at <hi>Chambers</hi> Sute) were ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver paid one penny for either labour or ſtuff. When the Houſe was fitted, he was upon ſome old account put in the <hi>Fleet,</hi> but removed himſelf again to the Kings Bench: But he quickly had a Cuſtomer for his Houſe, and let it to a very honeſt man for a good fine, and convenient rent, pretending a Leafe Parol from the head Landlady, and doubtleſs he had thoſe would have prov'd it, or ruin'd her, if he had been at liberty. But now being dead I think ſhe is well clear'd of a quarelſome Cuſtomer.</p>
            <p>Now getting again his liberty, he grew ſo confident, that whereas his former attempts were moſt of them upon ſuch, from whoſe weakneſs or obnoxiouſneſs he might hope for ſucceſs, but now he ſlies high, and ſets upon one, where he was ſure not to meet with any ſuch advantage: I mean Mr. <hi>Johnſon</hi> an Attorney of <hi>Cliffords-Inn,</hi> to whom he brought a Bond of 200 <hi>l.</hi> for pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of 100 <hi>l.</hi> to be put in Sute, and (as they ſay 'tis uſually done by wary men) deſired his note of the recept of it: So when Mr. <hi>Johnſon</hi> was intent upon his buſineſs, and looking over his Papers, <hi>Farr</hi> pilfer'd away the Bond, and in order to his father deſign, Mrs. <hi>Chadwick</hi> and another make <hi>affidavit,</hi> that Mr. <hi>John<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon</hi> had falſely and treacherouſly ſold the ſaid Bond to the Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant, the perſon therein concerned, and ſo commenced his ſute againſt him, and had he lived, this Term it had come to Tryal. When <hi>Farr</hi> was Convicted, and his papers look'd over, this ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Bond, and the foreſaid <hi>affidavit</hi> about it, were found wrapt
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:103523:27"/>up together. There was alſo found near 40 Warrants for Judge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments againſt ſeveral men, amongſt the reſt, two were there in pickle againſt his old friend <hi>Chambers;</hi> but they were by ſpecial order of the Lord Ch. Juſtice, all ſecured.</p>
            <p>And now I come to the buſineſs of Madam <hi>Stanier,</hi> the laſt, (and indeed deepeſt and moſt preſumptuous undertaking of his life) and ſuch an one, as (I think) was ſcarce ever acted under colour of Law; wherein, if deſiring to be particular, I be alſo large, I hope for the matter ſake, I ſhall not ſeem tedious.</p>
            <p>He had, without doubt, long deſigned an attempt upon her, but ſet it not on foot till <hi>Auguſt</hi> 1664. And then he cauſed his Mother <hi>Eliz. Farr</hi> to ſeal a Leaſe to him of the houſe wherein Mr. <hi>Stanier</hi> lived in St. <hi>Martins-lane</hi> in the Fields (to which houſe the ſaid <hi>Eliz. Farr</hi> had not the leaſt title, or any colour thereof.) In <hi>Michaelmas</hi> Term following, Mrs. <hi>Chadwick</hi> got <hi>S. S.</hi> Clerk to Mr. <hi>Jobſon</hi> Attorney in the Common-Pleas, to draw a Declaration againſt one <hi>Richard Pelar,</hi> as a caſual Ejector<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> pretending it was only to eject an ill Tenant that Mr. <hi>Farr</hi> had in a ſmall Tenement of his, in St. <hi>Martins-lane,</hi> of about 4 <hi>l.</hi>
               <hi>per. an.</hi> for non-payment of Rent: A true Copy of which Declaration ought to have been left with Mrs. <hi>Stanier,</hi> but that would have ſpoyled the plot. Therefore Mrs. <hi>Chadwick,</hi> by <hi>Farrs</hi> direction, falſely made <hi>affidavit,</hi> before Judge <hi>Tirrel,</hi> that ſhe had left a true Copy of the ſaid Declaration at the ſaid Houſe; and that on the 11 th. of <hi>February,</hi> ſhe went to the ſaid <hi>Robert Stanier,</hi> to know if he would defend the title of the ſaid Houſe, and that he anſwer'd, <hi>he had notice of the ſaid Declaration, but would not make any defence thereto.</hi> Upon this, <hi>Farr</hi> by a Motion in the Court of Common Pleas, obtain'd a Rule, That unleſs <hi>Mr. Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nier,</hi> the preſent Poſſeſſor of the ſaid Houſe, or ſome other, did ſhew cauſe within 14 days why Judgement ſhould not paſs, it ſhould be entered. <hi>Mr. Stanier</hi> having no knowledge nor no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice hereof, made no defence, and ſo Judgement was obtained by default, and thereupon a Writ of Poſſeſſion made by the ſaid <hi>S. S.</hi> directed to the Sheriff of <hi>Midd,</hi> dated <hi>Feb.</hi> 13.1664. On the 6th. of <hi>March</hi> following, <hi>Farr</hi> (with one <hi>Auſon</hi> a Bayliff, and 3 or 4 of his followers) did, by vertue of this Writ, break open,
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:103523:28"/>and forcibly enter'd the ſaid Houſe; and the better to accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pliſh his intended Villany, arreſted <hi>Mrs. Stanier</hi> by Bill of <hi>Midd.</hi> in an action of 100 <hi>l.</hi> debt (whereas ſhe owed him not a far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing) and violently forced her out of her Houſe into a Coach, and ſo-carried her away to <hi>Newgate.</hi> They alſo turned out of the Houſe one <hi>Mrs. Plummer,</hi> who lodged there. At night <hi>Farr</hi> fell to his work, ſending away all the Money, Jewels, Plate, Rings, and other things of value and ſmall bulk, by <hi>Mrs. Chad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wick,</hi> the Beds, Hangings, Pewter, and other more bulky goods by a Porter (whom afterwards they accidentally met withall, and he was an uſefull witneſs in the caſe) to the value of I 100 <hi>l.</hi> and and in Bonds, Bills, and other writings, to the value of 2000 <hi>l. Mrs. Stanier</hi> was deteined in priſon all night; but in the morn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing came to her one Mr. <hi>Meſſarvy</hi> her Kinſman, with a friend or two more, and bailed her out; And then (as it was but high time) went about ſecuring the goods that were in the Houſe out of <hi>Farrs</hi> hands; And by Petition to the Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Hide,</hi> ſetting out the whole matter of fact, obtained from his Lordſhip, on the 8th. of <hi>March,</hi> to ſend Mr. <hi>Cheiny</hi> one of his Tipſtaffs, for <hi>Farr</hi> (who ſtill continued in the Houſe) to come before him. <hi>Farr</hi> would not open the Door, nor be perſwaded to come to the Tipſtaff, upon pretence, that 'twas but a Trick, to get him out of Poſſeſſion. Whereupon Mr. <hi>Cheiny</hi> went and fetch'd my Lords Warrant, and a Conſtable to execute it: Upon ſight whereof, <hi>Farr</hi> came down, and opened the Doors, but would not let any one goe into the Houſe, for fear (as he pretended) they ſhould re-enter, and keep Poſſeſſion; but indeed his fear was, leſt it ſhould be diſcovered, how he had robb'd the Houſe. Coming before my Lord Chief Juſtice, he told his Lordſhip, That he had a good Title to the Hotſe, and had by Law obtained Poſſeſſion: My Lord told him, He would not diſpute that then; but he was ſure, he had no colour of right by Law to the Goods, and therefore he would not truſt them in his hands: VVhere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon <hi>Farr</hi> told his Lordſhip, That there was not a farthing worth of the Good touch'd: His Lordſhip then made him this Propoſition, <hi>viz.</hi> That he ſhould let <hi>Mrs. Stanier</hi> goe again into the Houſe, and have all her Goods, and he ſhould have ſecurity,
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:103523:28"/>that Poſſeſſion of the Houſe ſhould be re-delivered to him, at the end of one VVeek, after the beginning of <hi>Eaſter</hi> Term next, in caſe the Judgement obtained, by default ſhould be, by the Court of Common-Pleas, upon Examination, confirmed and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed: To this he conſented; but when he ſhould have per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed it, took the Key of the Door with him, and went his way. Upon the Oaths of ſeveral of the Neighbours, that the Goods were carried away by Night, the Houſe was ordered to be broke open, and was found empty: VVhereupon my Lord iſſued out his VVarrant, for the apprehenſion of <hi>Farr;</hi> and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing brought before him, and examined by him, was, by his VVarrant, committed to <hi>Newgate.</hi> His Lordſhip alſo granted his VVarrant, for the ſearching of <hi>Farr</hi>'s Houſe, in <hi>Turnagen-Lane,</hi> near <hi>Snow-Hill,</hi> where Mrs. <hi>Chadwick</hi> was, and denied entrance: VVhereupon the Conſtable Mr. <hi>Audley,</hi> broken open the Houſe, and apprehended her (who was alſo committed to <hi>Newgate</hi>) And here were found many of <hi>Mrs. Staniers</hi> Goods, as 13 rich Stone Rings, Linnen, Hangings, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and many of her VVritings. Her Pewter, mark'd with a Coat of Armes, <hi>Farr</hi> had chang'd, and ſold at one Mr. <hi>Griggs;</hi> pretendingn to him, that he had it for a Debt. The Goods thus found, were, by order of the Lord Chief Juſtice, inventory'd, and at the Tryal (where <hi>Mrs. Stanier</hi> did, by clear Evidence, prove her property to them) were, by Order of Court, reſtored. But there is yet wanting about 150 Pound in Money, about 110. Pound in Plate, a Neck-lace of Pearl, valued at 350 Pound, with ſome Rings, and other Goods. Mr. <hi>Meſſarvy,</hi> before mentioned, being, by the Lord Chief Juſtice, bound in a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cognizance of 40 Pound, to proſecute, had (by advice of a Council) an Indictment drawn againſt <hi>Richard Farr,</hi> and <hi>Elea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor Chadwick,</hi> for having, on the 6th. of <hi>March,</hi> &amp;c. fel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loniouſly broken, and forcibly entered, the Manſion Houſe of <hi>Robert Stanier</hi> Eſquire, his VVife being then within, and put her in fear of her Life; and ſtealing the Goods, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> according to the Inventory of them in Court produced. VVhich being ſufficiently proved, <hi>Farr</hi> would fain have made it to have been but a Cheat; but being not able to make out any Title, either
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:103523:29"/>to Houſe or Goods, but the Right to both, prov'd to be in <hi>Mrs. Stanier,</hi> Judgement paſs'd upon him, and Mrs. <hi>Chadwick,</hi> according to the Indictment, without benefit of Clergy. <hi>Farr</hi> begg'd heartily and pathetically to be Tranſported, or otherwiſe diſpoſed of; and not to be ſo ſeverely dealt withall, as to be cut off, for this his firſt Fault (as he call'd it) My Lord told him, That he had had warning enough by the Pillory, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> but he would take no warning; that he deſerved this long agoe, but now muſt not hope to eſcape it. Mrs. <hi>Chadwick</hi> laid claim to a great Belly, but by a Jury of VVowmen 'twas found other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe.</p>
            <p>One thing I ſhall here obſerve; that 'twas at this very Seſſions 7 years agoe, that <hi>Farr</hi> indicted Mrs. <hi>Stanier</hi> in the ſame place for her life, himſelf ſwearing againſt her, that ſhe had ſpoken treaſonable words againſt the then powers.</p>
            <p>But let us now follow him to his journeys end; after he was condemned, he was much preſs'd to confeſs where the reſt of Mrs. <hi>Staniers</hi> things were, but could not be prevailed with. Nay to one, who diſcourſing with him as to his future condition, urged the Doctrine of Reſtitution, he anſwered, they needed not to grudge him thoſe things which he muſt pay ſo dear for. When the Ordinary or Miniſter came to perform his Office, he ſeemed very penitent, and did receive the Sacrament; and upon the motion of one of the Keepers, he deſired his Wife might be ſent for, for a reconciliation; when ſhe came he asked her for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giveneſs, which ſhe willingly granted, but withall ſaid, that that vile woman (Mrs. <hi>Chadwick</hi>) ſhe thought was the chief inſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of eſtranging his affections from her, and was hardly hardly brought to forgive her, but at laſt ſhe was perſwaded to do it.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Farr</hi> Wife brought down her Son with her, and deſired her Husband to remember him, and do ſomething for him; he an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwered he was poor, and had nothing to leave, only he pull'd off a ſmall gold Ring from his finger, and gave him that.</p>
            <p>He was very willing to have ſaved Mrs. <hi>Chadwick,</hi> for the next day after ſentence, he deſired that a skilfull Midwife or two might be ſent for, alleging that he was ſure Mrs. <hi>Chadwick</hi> was
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:103523:29"/>with Child, for he had that morning laid his hand upon her Belly and felt the Child move, but the Midwife, when ſhe came, found her not with Child.</p>
            <p>He left with Mr. <hi>Jackſon</hi> the Keeper 5 <hi>l.</hi> to be diſpoſed of as he directed, <hi>viz.</hi> 50 <hi>s.</hi> in a Supper, 20 <hi>s.</hi> to be drank among the under-Keepers, 10 <hi>s.</hi> to the Ringers, and 20 <hi>s.</hi> he left the Ordinary to preach a Sermon at his interment: And being ask'd what Text, He firſt named, <hi>Bleſſed are the dead that dye in the Lord.</hi> The Ordinary thinking that not a ſuitable Text, He na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med 2ly. <hi>Lord lay not this ſin to their charge.</hi> Or 3ly. <hi>Except yee repent yee ſhall all likewiſe periſh.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>He alſo left with the Ordinary 20 <hi>s.</hi> for the Executioner, in lieu of his cloaths, for he had nothing under his Gown but a ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>milion Waſtcoat, and a pair or linnen Drawers.</p>
            <p>When they went to Execution (many thouſands from all parts of the City coming to ſee them) <hi>Farr</hi> and <hi>Chadwick</hi> were put in a Cart together, he was in a purple colour'd ſhagg Gown, ſhe in a black Gown, a black hood with a white Sarcenet hood un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der it. Near St. <hi>Giles</hi>'s Church, ſhe was obſerved to give away a couple of Rings which ſhe had in her Boſome. And a while after he eſpyed his old Adverſary <hi>Chambers</hi> following the Cart on Horſeback, at which he fell into paſſion, and deſired he might be taken out of his ſight, taxing him as the chief inſtrument of his death; ſo <hi>Chambers</hi> rid forward out of his ſight. When he was under the Gallows, and tyed up, he repeated over again how he would have his Legacies diſpoſed; and then turning to Mrs. <hi>Chadwick,</hi> he ſaid, <hi>My Dear, doſt thou forgive me?</hi> ſhe anſwer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, <hi>Yes I do forgive thee with all my heart, though thy acquain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance hath coſt me very dear.</hi> With that he reached to have kiſſed her, ſhe alſo bending forward to meet him, but the Halters <hi>Chambers</hi> asking <hi>Farr</hi> ſome Queſtions about himſelf, Mrs. <hi>Chad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wick</hi> pull'd him by the Arm, and would not let him enter into diſcourſe; ſo careful was ſhe of him, even to the laſt. When the Cart was ready to be drawn away, <hi>Farr</hi> crying out, <hi>Lord Jeſus receive my Spirit! Oh give me of the Water of Life! Oh gixe me of the Water of Life!</hi> He pull'd up his Leggs from the
<pb n="58" facs="tcp:103523:30"/>Cart, hanging himſelf ſome little ſpace before the Cart drew a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way VVhen they were dead, they were cut down, and put in two very compleat Elm Coffins, full of Hinges; and ſo, in a Coach, which, by the Coachman, and a Footman, being in Livery, appeared to be ſome Gentlemans, they were brought to <hi>Newgate</hi> Lodge, and from thence carried to <hi>Chriſt Church,</hi> where they had appointed themſelves to be interred, cloſe by each other.</p>
            <p>But there being gathered together ſo great a Multitude, and confuſed Rabble, the Ordinary thought not fit to preach, giving the 20 <hi>s.</hi> to his VVife, who (I think) poor VVoman, had need enough of it. But as things have happened, I think ſhe hath no great cauſe of ſorrow, for his former unkindneſs.</p>
            <p>And now having brought them to their Graves, by a bare Relation of Matter of Fact; I ſhall leave them there, quietly to reſt, covered with the Duſt, without any railing Reflections: Only,</p>
            <epigraph>
               <q>
                  <l>Diſce tu Lector.</l>
                  <l>Rarò antecedentem ſcele ſtum</l>
                  <l>Deſeruit pede paena claudo.</l>
               </q>
            </epigraph>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="publishers_advertisement">
            <p>There is now newly Publiſhed, an ingenous Book, written by a Perſon of Quality, Entituled, <hi>Europae Modernae Speculum:</hi> Or, a <hi>View</hi> of the ſeveral Empires, Kingdoms, Principalities, Seigneuries, and Common-wealths of <hi>Europe,</hi> in their Site, Government, Policy, different Intereſt, and mutual Aſpect, one towards another, from the <hi>Munſter</hi> Treaty, in the Year <hi>1684.</hi> to this preſent, <hi>1665. Alſo,</hi>
            </p>
            <p>An Exact Survey of the Affairs of the United <hi>Netherlands,</hi> eſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pecially as to their preſent Difference with <hi>England. Both ſold by</hi> T. Johnſon, <hi>at the</hi> Golden-Key <hi>in</hi> Cannon-Alley, <hi>near the Great North Door of St.</hi> Pauls</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:103523:30"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
